Where is this? Why am I here?
Oh yeah, I was with someone until just a moment ago.
With someone very important...
It's no good. My head is foggy and I can't remember.
Where did you come from? Where is your mother?
My mother?
Can't you fly?
How cute!
I wonder if it's okay to leave it here...
Okay, I'll walk away a little and turn around. If he doesn't follow me, then I'll leave him.
Oh, he's following me.
Do you want to come with me?
Okay, then let's go together.
Get set, go!
Hey, hey, wanna go to the beach?
Okay, sure! My bathing suit this year is super daring.
What?!
I mustn't cry. Hold it in.
Sora...
I'm going to be all alone again this summer, after all.
I couldn't get anyone to play with me.
They all know about it... that I'm not a normal girl.
It's that person from yesterday.
I really don't want to be all alone.
Such a long vacation... I don't want to be the only one all alone!
So I'm going to try talking to that guy.
If he seems like a nice person, I'll ask him to play with me.
Keep smiling, now, and try to act natural.
R-Ramen set!
Hello. Are you alone?
Well, you do seem to have pluck. I like that about you.
That's right. Yukito is a really nice guy.
Alright. He can stay.
I'm Kano Kirishima. Who are you?
I'm Kunisaki Yukito.
Do you have some free time, by any chance?
I guess...
Alright! I'll name you Freefreeplanetling Number 2!
Who's Number 1?
Me! And Potato is Number 3.
Piko.
And what do Freefreeplanetlings do?
They just have time on their hands.
That is the fate of all Freefreeplanetlings.
Right? We have nothing to do, do we, Potato?
Pikopiko!
Tohno Minagi-san. She's my classmate.
She's smart. She's at the top of our grade, and she's president of the Astronomy Club.
Oh, Yukito is flying like a leaf!
I had a dream.
That's nothing unusual. I have them too.
A strange dream about the sky.
I was in the sky. It was a world I'd never seen before.
See, when you sit like this, the clouds are above you.
But in my dream, the clouds were below my feet.
I could see the blue of the sea between the clouds.
But I couldn't tell how far it was to there.
Everything went on into infinity.
Is Kano taking a nap?
Yeah, because of last night too, I told her to rest.
Kano!
Huh?
Piko!
Kano!
Wake up! Kano!
What happened, Yukito-san?
I feel anxious... sort of nostalgic, and sort of melancholy.
What was that plume, anyway?
I don't know.
Let's let it go to the sky.
Then, I will keep it for you.
Please take good care of it, Minagi.
Sure.
Michiru?
Michiru.
The girl with wings continues to have sad dreams in the sky.
So, if you find her, please tell her many happy things.
And set her free from her sad dreams.
Yeah.
Are you smiling now?
Yes.
Really?
Then, keep smiling. Say bye-bye while smiling for me.
Are you smiling, Michiru?
Yeah.
Are you sad to go?
No, I'm not sad. I'm smiling, after all.
Minagi?
Michiru, bye-bye.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Nothing...
I messed up.
Are you crying?
No, I'm not crying.
I can play.
I have to try.
What's going on? Do you feel sick or something?
I'm okay! I'm okay!
Misuzu! What's going on?
Hey, get a hold of yourself!
She's done that ever since she was a little girl.
Right when I think she's making a friend, it happens.
I got dizzy all of a sudden and my feet got tangled.
I'm sorry that I made you worry.
Maybe you're slightly anaemic.
What should we do? Do you want to go to the hospital?
No, I'll be alright. I think I just need some rest.
Hey, Yukito-san...
What is it?
There's a connection between the person you're looking for and my dreams, isn't there?
I don't know... Probably not.
It's my other self in my dreams.
And, she is suffering now.
I'm going to try to see more dreams.
Because if I do that, they might help me understand.
Then, maybe I can help her.
Misuzu...
What?
I think I should leave soon.
If I stay with you any longer, neither one of us will survive.
So, I've decided to run away from you.
Then, bye-bye. Take care.
You, too. Stay strong. Stay strong, even if you're alone.
Yes, I'll do my best even if I'm alone. I'm a strong girl.
Excellent. Bye, now.
I've been alone until today. And I'll be alone from now on, too.
Even if I do my best, I just cause trouble for other people.
There's not a single good thing about me.
I should've just continued to be alone, like I've always been.
I should never have come to love someone.
I'll go to sleep.
I don't care if I never wake up again.
Why? I thought I wouldn't be able to get up anymore...
Yukito! Where are you? You came back, didn't you?
Misuzu...
I'm here.
I'm here!
Yukito-san!
Misuzu...
Yukito-san...
Yukito-san... Yukito-san!
Misuzu...
I'm going to do my best.
I'll show you.
So, so please don't go anywhere. Stay by my side.
Yukito-san...
You'll be alright.
You're a strong girl, so I'm sure you'll be able to reach it...
that goal that no one else has been able to reach.
I'm sure you'll make it.
I'll always be near you. I'll never forget you.
I'll be with you.
Yukito-san?
Yukito-san?!
I'll be with you forever.
Yukito! Wait! Don't go...
Do your best, Misuzu.
Stay strong until you reach the goal, Misuzu.
Okay. I'll do my best. Let's do our best, Yukito-san.
Sora...
I had a dream about the person I love.
Yukito-san came back to me in the end after all, didn't he?
He gave me something precious, you know...
Let's rest for a bit.
I guess I'll have my usual; the weird juice.
It's that person...
I had a tough time, too.
I worked very hard to keep you here with me.
You aren't my child.
You'll be taken to the Tachibana residence someday.
That's why I ignored you even though we lived together.
It would be hard for us to separate if I fell in love with you, right?
I always kept my feelings subdued so that I will be fine no matter when you leave, but there was no point.
I love you.
I can't lie to myself any longer,
so I've decided. I'll make you my child.
I was on my knees in front of the Tachibana residence the whole time.
In the end, I had more patience.
Yeah... I felt like I had to show off for you,
so I raised my hand even though I didn't know the answer.
You came and gave me a whack in front of everyone.
V!
Oh, you're up, Misuzu?
What's wrong? Are you still sleepy?
Who?
Who are you, oba-san?
What is the meaning of this?!
Keisuke...
Who is that?
Misuzu, I'm your father.
Now, say "thank you" to your aunty.
Keisuke! Wait, Keisuke!
Three days. Please wait three days.
If, at that time, she says she doesn't want to stay with me...
Then it's okay. You can take Misuzu away.
I'm begging you, Keisuke!
Three days...
Can I regain our mother-child relationship in that time?
Misuzu! What's wrong?
Got it!
I'll be happy if I can just spend one day with you.
That's all I wish for.
Misuzu.
It's the sea.
Isn't the sea... beautiful?
It was so far. How many years did it take us to get here, I wonder?
We could have enjoyed this beautiful view anytime we wanted.
What in the world were we doing?
Is it alright now?
She's heavy. It's been a long time since you carried her.
It's thanks to you that she's grown this big.
Thank you.
Oh, yeah... Let her hold on to this.
She loves this doll.
She should be able to sleep comfortably if she's holding this.
If she's still fussy, give her this to drink.
It's her favourite juice.
Got it. Bye.
That fool! What is he doing?!
Misu...
Mama!
Misuzu!
That's right, I'm your mother.
Mama...
It's summer vacation, isn't it?
Summer vacation for just the two of us.
But that's okay. We can play together.
Listen, Mum. I want you to go ahead a little.
Why? Is there a reason?
Yes. Take Sora with you.
Over here, Misuzu. I'm over here.
It's enough, right?
Huh? What is?
I did my best, right?
I can go to my goal now, right?
Are you tired already?
Alright, after you reach me, we'll go home and play cards or something.
No... My goal, the goal I've been aiming at for a long time.
Huh?
I... did my best, so it's enough now, right?
I can rest, right?
I'm sorry, Mummy.
But I was able to finish everything, so...
so I'll go to my goal, okay?
One more time... the summer vacation when I thought I'd do my best,
the summer vacation that started on the day I met Yukito-san.
Even though lots happened, even though it hurt sometimes or was painful sometimes,
I'm glad I tried my hardest!
No, it starts now!
I'm saying it all starts now!
Goal!
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta itsudatte yowakute
眩しくて逃げた　いつだって弱くて
They were so dazzling, I ran away - I was always weak.
ano hi kara kawarazu
あの日から変わらず
I let go, frustrated by the fact...
itsumademo kawarazu ni irarenakatta koto
いつまでも変わらずにいられなかったこと
...that I couldn't stay unchanged since that day...
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
...couldn't stay unchanged forever.
ano tori wa mada umaku tobenai kedo
あの鳥はまだうまく飛べないけど
That bird still can't fly well.
itsuka wa kaze o kitte shiru
いつかは風を切って知る
But someday I'll know the feeling of gliding through the wind.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは 夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
fuku kaze ni suashi o sarashite
吹く風に素足をさらして
exposing their bare feet to the blowing wind.
tooku ni wa osanakatta hibi o
遠くには幼かった日々を
We place in the distance the days of our childhood,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.