Sora,
I dreamed about someone I love.
Yukito-san really did come back after everything, right?
He gave me something important, right?
So...
I can't give up on something like this, right?
It's all right.
I can do my best, even by myself.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Today, I'm going to try to go outside,
even though walking is painful.
I'll try my best.
Let's rest a bit.
I guess I'll get this,
the weird juice.
It's that person,
the one who was living with us until a while ago.
Who is she?
She seems vaguely familiar.
Episode 11
So the freeloader left?
Well, he'll eventually come back if he has nowhere else to go.
I had a hard time too.
I was trying my best so that you could stay here forever.
Eh?
You aren't my child.
You'll be taken to the Tachibana residence someday.
That's why I ignored you even though we lived together.
It would be hard for us to separate if I fell in love with you, right?
I always kept my feelings subdued so that I will be fine no matter when you leave, but there was no point.
I love you.
I can't lie to myself any longer,
so I've decided.
I'll make you my child.
I was on my knees in front of the Tachibana residence the whole time.
In the end, I had more patience.
You didn't have to do that.
Eh?
I've decided that I will do my best by myself and that I won't trouble anyone anymore.
Misuzu!
What happened, Misuzu?!
Were you really that sick?
I thought that you just had a cold.
Your feet won't move?
Let's go see the doctor.
It'll probably get better.
You know, the female doctor at the clinic.
She can probably help you.
This can't be healed in a hospital.
Eh?
Yukito-san and I discovered the reason for my illness.
My other self is in the sky, and she's carrying a burden by herself.
That's why my body froze.
You always spout those fantasies.
Hey, Mummy?
Let's keep on living like before, without bothering with each other.
Eh?
Let's live our respective lives.
I'll keep striving by myself.
W-Why are you saying such things?
Are you angry because I left you alone for a long time?
All right.
If you don't want to go to the hospital, I don't mind.
I'll take good care of you.
But two is better than one.
Let's do our best together!
Okay, Misuzu?
What do you think? Is it good?
I see.
Sorry.
I'll make it tasty next time, okay?
I don't want any.
Your cooking is never good.
Children grow up eating their parents' cooking, even if it isn't good.
I'm sorry.
Was it that bad?
That's not it.
It's just that you'll get sick too if you're friendly with me.
Did you dream that too?
Listen, Misuzu,
I'm not scared of any sickness.
If I get sick, I'll be happy.
That's proof that we became friends, right?
Here, eat up.
It tastes good.
Mummy.
What is it?
Where should I cut it to?
I'll leave that up to you, Mummy.
Hmm...
Then I'll cut it to where you look your cutest, okay?
Okay.
Mummy, you have more wrinkles now.
Do you want me to shave your head?
I'm kidding.
You're young.
Once, at an open house, I was the only kid who was happy because everyone else's mums were old.
You were crying because you got the answer wrong.
Yes.
I thought that I needed to be cool, so I raised my hand without knowing the answer.
Then, you hit me in front of everyone.
That's because you said "Gao", your favourite phrase.
Discipline, discipline.
Thanks to that, Misuzu grew up into a good girl.
That's true.
You've matured quite a lot.
You're saying that phrase less often now too.
Misuzu.
Misuzu?
Ah well, it's easier this way.
I'll just have to make it match.
Oh, shoot!
Now the other side is too short!
Huh?
I was able to balance both sides, but...
It's so short.
I'm sorry!
I feel like a small child again,
Mummy's child.
Indeed.
Let's redo everything from here.
Let's redo it together, okay?
Yes.
It starts from here, right?
V!
Hey, it's almost the summer festival, right?
Yup, that's right. I forgot that.
I want to go with you.
Of course I'll take you.
I want to go to the beach after that,
because I've never gone with you before.
You have so many places you want to visit, don't you?
Yes.
I want to do many fun things with you.
Yes, let's do lots of fun things together.
Let's fill your diary up with fun things.
Um... Mummy?
I'll remember your smile.
I'll always remember, no matter what.
Your...
I don't know what you're talking about.
What do you mean, Misuzu?
Misuzu, you were awake?
What's wrong?
Are you still sleepy?
Who are you?
Hmm?
[Note: oba-san = an older woman whom one doesn't know well]
Who are you, oba-san?
You forgot?!
You said that we would work our hardest together!
Mama?
Yes, me!
Mama went far away.
You don't have to remember stuff like that.
I'm your substitute mother!
It's okay.
From today, I'll try to restore her memory.
It's all right if I'm Haruko-obasan until the day you see me as your mother again.
Misuzu!
I borrowed this.
Look, you can go outside with this.
It hurts, and I can't walk.
That's what this wheelchair is for.
Come here.
[Note: Haruko refers to herself as "oba-san", showing her acceptance of the role]
I'll push you.
It's more fun playing cards by myself.
Hey, let's play together.
It feels good to be outside in the sun, and there are lots of fun things to do.
The wind is blowing.
It's blowing, eh?
The sun is sizzling.
Yeah, it is, eh?
The cicadas are chirping.
So much that it's almost noisy, eh?
It feels nice.
Is that so?
I'm glad.
What is the meaning of this?!
Keisuke.
Who is he?
Misuzu, I'm your father.
You know that this girl can't be in large crowds.
That's why I left her with you in this quiet town.
But it was a mistake.
Haven't you heard?
She is my child now.
I already have your parents' permission.
She's my child.
She belongs to Ikuko and me.
Is the Kamio residence such a convenient place to drop her off when she's in the way and pick her up when you remember?
I can't leave her with you, where she gets sicker.
[Note: He is being distant and formal by using the standard language]
Stop using that standard language!
Just hearing it disgusts me!
Oba-san, you're scary.
Ah, I'm sorry for yelling.
Oba-san?
T-That's not how it is!
Just a while ago she called me "Mummy" all the time.
Now, let's go, Misuzu.
Say "thank you" to Oba-san.
Hey, where's your "thank you"?
Thank you.
No!
No! No!
Don't take Misuzu away!
Misuzu was alone for a long time.
Whose fault was that?
Wasn't it ours?!
That's why I decided to stay with her forever.
Are you still going to push her around because of our arguments?!
Haruko.
I'm uneducated, so I don't know how to sugarcoat it, but I know that I want to be with her much more than you do.
That's for sure!
Then let's ask her.
Misuzu, do you want to be with Haruko-obasan from now on?
Oba-san?
Yes.
Do you want to keep living with her from now on?
Keisuke.
Keisuke, wait.
Three days.
Just wait three days.
If she says at that time that she doesn't want to be with me anymore, then I won't mind!
I won't mind if you take Misuzu away!
Please!
Keisuke!
Three days.
Can I regain the time that we've lost with just that?
[Note: Haruko uses "-chan" to distance herself from Misuzu, just like an aunt]
Misuzu-chan, you really like dinosaurs, don't you?
This is a Maiasaura.
It means "good mother dinosaur."
Heh.
It's just like me.
This is a Velociraptor.
It means "speedy thief."
Hah! That one is like Keisuke.
I wonder which one of us is the thief.
It's hot.
It is,
but it's a short walk, so you'll have to bear it.
It should be cooler when we arrive at the ocean.
There, let's eat our boxed lunch,
the boxed lunch that I made.
I want to go home.
Don't say that.
Our lunch will be wasted.
Go home.
There are sweet egg omelettes too.
I made them at your request.
Let's make it a fun day, okay?
No.
Are you really going home?
I'm going home.
Then what's going to happen to the boxed lunch that I made?
I don't know.
I see.
Then do whatever you want!
If you want to play by yourself that much, then go home by yourself!
Idiot!
It's hot.
I feel dizzy.
Gao.
Let's go home.
Let's go home, Misuzu.
I've known this all along.
I'm really not cut out to be a mother.
That's what it means.
What I've been doing isn't...
Misuzu, what happened?!
Get it out.
Cicada.
All right, I'll get it out!
I'm the cicada-getting-oba-san!
Cicada-getting-oba-san?
That's right.
A scaredy-cat like you needs one, right?
Yes.
There?!
I got it!
You can play at ease now, right?
Yes.
I see.
Then I'll go.
It's all right... for me to stay?
Yes.
I won't ask for too much anymore.
It's all right if I can just stay with you all day long.
That's all that I wish for.
Today is the day I promised Keisuke.
That fool, he'll come to see you again.
Then you'll answer that you want to go with him, right?
You'll say that you don't want to be with me anymore, right?
Summer vacation will still continue, but our time together ends today.
Is it all right?
Yes.
It's all right.
I see.
Hey, Keisuke,
there's one last place I want to take her.
Can I have a bit more time?
Misuzu, it's the ocean.
This is the ocean.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
We've come so far.
I wonder how many years it took for the two of us to come here together.
We should have been able to see this beautiful scenery as often as we wanted; what exactly were we doing?
Is it all right now?
She's heavy, since it's been a long time since you held her.
It's all thanks to you that she was able to grow this big.
Thank you.
Oh, right.
Give this to her.
She loves this stuffed animal.
I think she'll calm down and sleep if she holds this.
If she still whines, have her drink this.
It's her favourite juice.
I understand.
See you.
Don't you have to go?
The princess is leaving.
Idiot!
What are you doing?!
Misu...
Mama!
Misuzu!
That's right.
I'm your mother.
Mama.
After that, the two of them talked in the twilight for a long time.
Then I'll bring a doctor I can trust, so will you have her examined?
I finally understood.
The person who was by Misuzu's side after all this time was...
...Misuzu's mother.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
I had wings.
They were pure white wings, and I was flying.
I see.
What a nice dream.
No, it was a sad dream,
the saddest dream in the world.
But this is the end of my dream.
From now on, I'm going to be by your side,
always and forever.
Final Episode