What I'm looking for might be the other you.
On the other side of this sky, there is a girl with wings.
She spreads those wings and continues to be blown by the wind from the distant past, just like long ago.
My mother passed away before she told me any more details.
Since then, my companions on the road have been just the story of the girl in the sky and this doll.
Yukito-san, are you searching for the same girl that your mother sought?
Well, there's no way that you'd be that girl, though.
Many people have visions of flying in the sky.
That girl can fly too, right?
Yeah.
She has wings.
Wow.
I want wings too.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
I'm home!
Hey, freeloader, here's a gift!
Oh, a sloth.
Isn't this better and more lovable than a dirty doll?
After all, I have to make you hurry and make money so you can leave.
It's cute.
Episode 2
A glass after work really is the best!
I feel like I live for these times!
All right, freeloader, first up tonight is the slightly-cryable-at-emotionally-moving-confession-of-love corner!
Do it yourself!
Oh, Misuzu, are you sleepy?
Mm... I think so...
Come here. I'll let you use my lap as a pillow.
Eh?! I-It's okay; it's not like I'm still a child.
I'll go to sleep now.
Good night.
Good night!
Ah, she ran away.
Do you often let her use your lap as a pillow?
Stupid! It was a joke.
As if that kid would cuddle with someone as pathetic as me!
That girl... Did she say "gao" today too?
Yeah.
I hit her each time she said it.
For some reason, when she was younger, she thought that a chick was a dinosaur's child.
Then, when she saw a chick at a summer festival booth, she really wanted it.
But at that time, we were poor, so we couldn't buy it.
Ever since then, she's had the habit of saying "gao" whenever something happens.
I'm not cut out to be a parent.
I should have remained alone.
What's more, that girl is weird.
Weird?
However, it seems that she is fine when she is with you,
so if possible, stay friends with her forever,
since it's already impossible for me now.
Come! It's the start of a fun puppet show!
What's this?
It's kind of creepy.
I have a feeling that it'll be in my dreams, in a bad way.
Let's go, let's go!
Hey!
Give me my payment!
It doesn't work at all!
Piko.
Oh, you again?
Did you say that your name was Potato?
Pikkori.
Piko.
Piko pikoo.
Piko piko pika.
What are you trying to imitate?
Is your daughter well?
Yes.
She says that white rice is yummy and eats many second-helpings, so it makes making meals worthwhile.
Please tell your daughter not to upset her stomach.
I'll tell her.
See you.
Now then...
What are you doing loitering in front of my place all this time?
Now, let's go home, shall we...
Hey! Don't try so hard to ignore me.
Oh, Potato, what are you doing?
You know him?
Oh? Yukito-kun?
Yukito-kun is talking to Onee-chan!
Sign: Kirishima Clinic
Wow, you're good.
It seems that Potato has become your fan too.
Wait, did you say Kunisaki Yukito-kun?
You have impressive skill, but I think that making money from that trick is impossible.
Piko?
Piko!
Despite what it seems, I've been wandering from town to town, living off just this trick.
Wow!
Then you've made loooooooooots of money in this town too, right?
Oh, you haven't?
Hey, what do you think of working part-time at this clinic?
My name is Kirishima Hijiri.
I'm the only doctor here ever since my parents passed away.
I was looking for someone to do odd jobs.
Why bamboo?
I'm so happy!
I've wanted to do this at least once.
Why is today's lunch nagashi soumen?
In this house, if Kano says nagashi soumen, we eat nagashi soumen.
This is obviously an unfair seating arrangement.
Why's that?
You'd eat a lot if you didn't sit there.
Piko.
Piko...
Well, I'll see you tomorrow at the same time.
You'll pay me more, right?
Okay, as special treatment, I'll let you perform puppet shows in front of our place.
Don't worry, I'll let you eat lunch too.
It was fun!
Let's play again tomorrow, Yukito-kun!
Pikopiko.
See you!
Piko pikopikoooo!
Did I make a mistake by accepting the job?
Jeez, this town really doesn't have many people passing by.
I guess traffic accidents must be uncommon too.
Sign: Niinuma Rice and Liquor Shop
Oh, I'm sorry.
Ah, no, it's my fault.
Thank you very much.
D-Don't mind it.
It's my responsibility too for bumping into you.
But why do you have such a large load?
My daughter enjoys rice and eats well, so I just...
Thank you very much.
Oh, this isn't much, but...
N-N-No, it's okay.
I can't accept...
No.
It's not much, but please accept this.
Does this town not operate on any currency?
Besides that, what kind of daughter can eat that much rice?
Misuzu is late.
Oh, a sloth!
So cuuuuute...
Wow, almost like a smaller version of Misuzu...
Hey, what happened to your parents?
Hmm?
Are you lost by any chance?
Want to eat it?
It's yummy and cute.
Decide whether it's yummy or cute.
It's cute and yummy.
Oh.
Oh, Yukito-san, who's this girl?
Apparently, she's lost.
What's your name?
Six years old.
What an incredible name.
Yukito-san, you be quiet.
What's your name?
You say that before your age, right?
Shino Saika, six years old.
Shino-san.
Byebye.
Mmhmm, byebye.
That girl has to be hospitalized now.
She's sick?
Is it serious?
No, it seems that it's not that bad.
And she says that she's fine because sloth became her friend.
I see.
I saw a dream.
Well, of course you see dreams.
I do too.
A mysterious dream.
A dream of the sky.
I was in the sky.
There was a world that I had never seen before.
See, if I'm like this, the clouds are above me,
but in my dream, the clouds were packed beneath my feet.
From the gaps between the clouds, I could see the bright blue of the ocean.
But I couldn't even tell how far it was
because everything extended endlessly.
Say,
did you have wings in your dream?
Eh?
I don't know; I didn't notice.
It's better if you don't talk to strangers about that.
It's all right.
I've only told you.
Wow, it somehow fits so naturally.
Do you have different ones?
The rest are too small.
Mm. smells nice.
What's this?
A boxed lunch.
I made this one with utmost care, so it's extremely delicious.
Boxed lunch?
You went to the trouble of...
Please deliver it to Kano.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
Kano is at school again today to take care of the animals.
If you eat it on the way there...
I'll deliver it carefully and quickly.
Can we stop by the book store?
There are quite a number of students.
So the ones here have supplemental classes, club activities or student government, eh?
Piko.
This might be a good opportunity.
Everyone, please welcome my puppet show with much applause!
Woohoo!
Kunisaki, you're the best!
Everybody, hey!
Love and peace!
Kunisaki, you're the best!
There's no way that could happen.
Piko?
Hm?
Piko.
If I take such a weird creature in, the high school might erupt in a great panic.
Don't move from there until I tell you to.
Pikkori.
There's something I'd like to ask.
Yes?
I've come to deliver a boxed lunch to someone named Kirishima Kano.
Do you know where she is?
Kanorin?
[note: "-rin" is an ending put on names to make them sound cuter]
Kanorin... maybe she's still in the nurse's office?
Nurse's office?
No, no.
She said she was going to the rooftop because she wanted to feel the wind.
She fell saying "kyuu~" after mumbling something.
I think it's just a little light-headedness.
I see.
So you worried about me.
You're okay now, right?
Geez, you're overreacting.
I just felt a little dizzy.
I see.
Isn't the sky so high?
Yukito-kun, can't you fly in the sky?
There's no way I can fly.
But you can move a doll.
Those things are completely unrelated.
Come to think of it, you said something like "If you could use magic," right?
Oh! That?
Yes, because I can use magic.
Huh?
That's a bit of a lie.
I can't use it until I become an adult.
But I've already decided what I'll do with my first spell.
What are you going to do?
It's a secret.
I'll tell you what I'll do second, though.
I don't particularly want to hear.
Aww?
Listen!
If you don't listen, it'll come out of your stomach, tear through crunchcrunching,
and humankind will be unable to match their strength, so it'll be like "Oh, what a problem!"
"The Earth, the Earth is in great trouble," eh?
Yes.
You have to protect the Earth, the Earth!
Okay, what do you want to do second?
Um, well...
I want to fly in the sky.
Magic to fly in the sky...
Hey!
Kunisaki Yukito!
Don't attack me so suddenly!
Why are you angry,
when I actually bothered to talk to you?
Shut up!
My head is spinning.
What a dirty doll!
Oh, it's mine.
It's so worn.
Poor thing.
You're suffering under a stupid master, aren't you?
Don't say that so poignantly!
All right, I'll save you!
Huh?
See you!
Hey, wait!
Over here!
Are you a butt-shaking-ling?!
Hey, how far are you going?!
Over here!
Stop it...
already!
Oh, Minagi!
It's all right!
After all, Minagi is the one fixing it.
Now, say "thank you".
Why are you telling me that?!
Ta-da.
It's done.
Wow, it came out nice.
Whoa... You're good.
Eh-hen!
[note: Japanese sound for showing pride.]
It must be a very important doll to you,
since you're always carrying it around.
Yeah, I guess.
The shape of an important memory.
Eh?
Am I wrong?
No,
that might be it.
You ruined the mood!
Shut up!
Presenting: rice ticket
[on the ticket: Worldwide Rice Ticket 1000 Yen]
Eh?
You're hungry, right?
Isn't Tohno-san great?
Not only is she great at studying, but she can sew as well.
Well?
Where are we headed?
Where many people congregate.
If you do a puppet show there, you'll have many customers.
Oh.
It's Mummy.
Exactly what kind of job does she have?
It's a secret.
Maybe she went and prayed at the shrine.
Shrine?
Yup, that's where we're headed.
There is no one here.
It's almost time for the summer festival.
Then, this shrine will be full of people
because children from the town will come.
The kids from this town are all unruly.
Waah, wait!
What is it?
Um...
Since we've come this far, I thought we should play some more.
Let's play hide-and-seek.
Huh?
Hide-and-seek.
I want to play it with you.
How old do you think we are?
Then... Then... Bug catching.
Gao.
Oh, a fish.
I want to catch fish.
You don't care what we play, do you?
Since it's summer vacation, I want to play as much as I can.
Hey, Misuzu!
I'm going now, got it?!
Huh?
Come to think of it, do you still believe
that when a chick grows up, it'll become a dinosaur?
Geez, I know already.
When a chick grows up, it'll become a chicken.
Actually, what I wanted wasn't a chick or a dinosaur's child.
I heard that you cried all day.
It didn't matter what it was as long as Mummy bought it for me.
What a fun day!
Really?
I'm glad.
I haven't had a birthday this fun, so I'm really glad.
Today is... your birthday?
Yes.
Why did you keep quiet about something that important?
Huh?
Because...
If I knew, I would have tried to get you a present, at least.
[Paper: rice ticket]
Yukito-san?
Go on home.
No one would watch a puppet show at night, eh?
Oh, it's over already?
Huh?
Show me, even if it's just a little.
Wow, great.
Hm...
But a child probably wouldn't turn to watch this.
It's none of your business!
Oh, excuse me.
What's this?
I visited some acquaintances, but they weren't home.
I'll give it to you.
A thank you gift for showing me something unusual.
It's really good.
Aren't you lucky that I was given a cake?
Yup, and the number of candles matches my age.
I wonder if he was planning to celebrate someone's birthday.
Does Haruko not remember that today is your birthday?
Mummy's busy, so...
Pretty...
How is it, are you satisfied?
Yes, I'm happy.
Then let's go home.
Kano...
Eh?
Hey, Kano!
The shrine again?
I think that she came here.
Oh.
For example...
the number of stars in the heavens...
in the mountains... the number of trees...
The number... of grass blades...
Kano!
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
At least work your salary's worth.
Potato!
Pikopiko!
Magical powers.
The world is full of mystery.
Isn't she always weird?
No, not like that.
Oh, if there's nothing, then it's all right.
What are you talking about?
I won.
V!
Help me!
I can't do it well at all!
Episode 3
Piko piko!