Come to think of it, I feel that everything that has happened so far was a trial for me to become your real mother.
[Sign: Misuzu-chin is resting]
Your feet not moving and you losing your memory were all trials for us to redo everything from the beginning.
Mama.
Misuzu!
Misuzu, hold on!
Where does it hurt?
I'll massage it!
It hurts! It hurts, Mama!
Here?
Does it hurt here?
No.
Your feet?
Hands?
W-Wings.
My wings... hurt.
After a while, Misuzu will begin to forget about me and about you too.
Then, after seeing her final dream, she'll probably die.
It's a lie, right?
If she falls asleep, if she dreams, she'll...
Misuzu!
You'll go to the summer festival, right?
You'll see the summer festival with me, right?
I want to go to the festival.
I want a dinosaur's baby.
You're talking about chicks, right?
There's probably a stall selling them.
Can I buy... a dinosaur?
Yes, let's eat something delicious.
Let's make tomorrow a really fun day!
So get better, Misuzu!
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Misuzu, it's morning.
It's the day of the summer festival.
Festival.
Final Episode
Please, God,
do something.
Onee-chan!
I'm an idiot.
There's no way they'd hold the festival.
Miracles won't happen.
There's no way that a god can exist.
What did this girl do?!
Didn't she wait like a good girl!
Wasn't she looking forward to the summer festival a lot?!
Why isn't she rewarded?!
It's the same as that time.
In the end, I'm never able to give you anything, am I?
Mama.
Where's the dinosaur's baby?
Why?
Why is it here?
I threw it away.
So you were watching all this time.
Misuzu.
Misuzu, wake up.
What is it, Mama?
There's the dinosaur, right there.
Let's go get it together, okay?
Here, try your best.
Yes.
I'll help you too.
This is a happy memory for the both of us.
Let's treasure it and raise it together.
I'm tired already.
I'm sleepy.
No!
Do your best with me.
Your friend is here too.
We're all here.
Let's be happy together.
Just a little more.
We can reach our happiness.
See?
You caught it.
Yay!
It's my birthday present to you.
I couldn't give it to you all this time we've been together, but will you accept it now?
Yes, I'm happy.
Really?
Aren't you glad, Misuzu?
It's cute.
It goes "Gao!"
Gao!
Thank you, God.
Mummy.
She hasn't slept for a long time, has she?
For my sake.
Oh, no.
I was asleep just now, right?
Sorry.
No, let's sleep.
I want to sleep with you.
What should I do?
If you sleep and dream, your pain will worsen, right?
No, it doesn't hurt anymore.
Eh?
It hasn't hurt for a while now.
I wonder why.
Really?
It really doesn't hurt?
No.
So I want to sleep.
I'll sleep and recover.
I see.
I'm so glad.
Isn't it good, Misuzu?
Since you did your best,
you were rewarded, right, Misuzu?
Misuzu...
No...
This isn't a cracker.
You can't eat it.
I'm sorry for lying to you, Mummy,
but you wouldn't rest unless I did.
Yukito-san.
I'll write in my diary.
Diary
Misuzu?
I fell asleep.
Does your body hurt?
Do you remember me?
Mummy, good morning!
The sun is bright.
That means it'll be a good day.
Mummy, I had a dream last night, too.
A dream?
You start hurting whenever you have dreams, right?
It's all right.
I don't hurt anywhere.
What's more, my dreams will end today.
Really?
There's really nothing wrong, right?
You don't hurt anywhere, right?
I'm all right.
V!
I see.
The freeloader said something about you having your last dream, but that was a mistake, right?
I was apprehensive.
Those days were like nightmares to me.
But it's finally over, right?
Mummy.
I can't tell you to stop crying anymore; I'm a crybaby too.
[Note: Said in kansai-ben; Misuzu is imitating her mother]
You mustn't cry.
That's true.
I mustn't cry when there's nothing to be sad about, right?
My dream last night was about a dinosaur with wings.
It was flying, looking like it felt good, and saying "Gao."
Is that so?
I was flying even higher than that.
I looked behind my shoulder;
I had wings.
They were pure white wings, and I was flying in the sky.
I see.
What a nice dream.
No, it was a sad dream,
the saddest dream in the world.
But this is the end of my dream.
From now on, I'm going to be by your side,
always and forever.
Ah, isn't it a really nice day?
[Note: Again, Misuzu says "really" in kansai-ben]
Yes, it feels really nice.
It smells like summer.
Yes, it does.
What kind of smell does it have?
The smell of the tide.
Yup, that's it.
The smell of the sun.
Yup, that's also true.
Mummy's smell.
Yup, that too.
Hey! I don't want it to reek with my smell.
It smells a lot like you.
Really?
Yes, this summer smelled a lot like you.
The smell of my precious mummy.
If it reeked of that, it would suck.
That would suck.
But it was a good smell.
Is that so?
I'm glad.
Yes, I'm glad.
It's hot.
Yeah, it's hot all right.
Hey, Misuzu, do you want me to guess what you're thinking?
Sure.
I want to drink juice.
Wow, you're good.
Anyone would have been able to guess that.
I want this.
This again?
You really like this one, don't you?
Which one should I get?
I recommend the Gel-lun juice.
Really?
Gooey?! It's hard!
Why would I want juice like this?!
Don't throw it away!
You drink this by squeezing.
Like this?
Well, it isn't bad...
It's summer vacation.
It's a summer vacation with just the two of us.
It's all right; we'll play together.
Hey, Mummy?
I want you to go on ahead by yourself.
Why?
You want me to do something?
Yes.
Take Sora with you too.
Is this far enough?
Yes, wait there.
Don't push yourself too much!
Mummy, keep standing there.
No matter what happens, don't come.
I'm going to do my best.
I'll do my best to walk over there.
Because Mummy, you're my goal.
I see.
I'm the goal.
Yes, you and Sora are the goal.
There's no need to hurry.
I'll wait as long as you want.
Yes.
Are you all right?
V!
Misuzu, here.
I'm here.
That's right, slow and steady.
If you keep working hard like that, you'll definitely recover.
Let's do our best together, okay?
Okay, Misuzu?
It's enough, right?
Huh? What is?
I did my best, right?
I can go to my goal now, right?
Are you tired already?
All right, after you reach me, we'll go home and play cards or something.
No,
my goal, the goal I've been aiming at for a long time.
I... did my best, so it's enough now, right?
I can rest, right?
You mean it hurts?
You've been hurting all this time?
Don't come!
That's a lie.
Say it's a lie.
You're going to start recovering, right?
The bad dreams were supposed to have ended, right?!
I'm sorry, Mummy.
But I was able to finish everything, so...
so I'll go to my goal, okay?
No, Misuzu.
Don't come.
You can't leave!
It's just started!
Didn't we start our lives anew yesterday?!
We're going to take it back,
the happy life that should have started ten years ago.
We're going to take it back, starting now!
Our happiness has just started!
No, we did everything.
It's enough already.
A lifetime's worth of happiness was crammed into this summer.
No!
That's wrong!
There are lots of things I still want to do,
lots of things I want to do with my beloved Misuzu!
All of that starts now!
One more time... the summer vacation when I thought I'd do my best,
the summer vacation that started on the day I met Yukito-san.
Even though lots happened, even though it hurt sometimes or was painful sometimes, I'm glad I tried my hardest!
Because my goal was to be happy...
Because I wasn't all alone...
So...
That's why...
I'll go to my goal now, okay?
No, it starts now!
I'm saying it all starts now!
Goal.
ano umi dokomademo aokatta tooku made
That eternally blue ocean stretched into the distance...
ano michi dokomademo tsuzuiteta massugu ni
That road extended endlessly in a line...
I've finally reached it.
The place I've always looked for.
The place of happiness.
The place of... eternal happiness.
ichiban hayaku sunao ni waratta mono gachi
The first one to display a genuine smile wins.
No!
I don't want that!
Mummy,
thank you.
ichiban sukina ano hito waratteru
The one I love most is smiling.
Misuzu...!
You taught me everything.
How to escape from living alone!
dareyorimo tooku ni itte mo koko kara mata waratte kureru
Will you still smile at me from here even if I go farther away than anyone else?
Don't leave me behind!
Don't leave me alone!
I don't need anything else.
I don't need friends, new clothes, luxuries, or anything!
Just being with you is enough for me.
hitomi wo tojireba futto natsu no hi no nioi
If I close my eyes, I suddenly sense the smell of a summer day.
[Kamio Haruko, Class 1-4]
Let's live together happily at the Kamio house!
Okay, Misuzu?
Misuzu!
ano kawa asonderu futarikiri dono darake
The two of us are playing in the river, covered in mud.
I spent the days since then crying and crying.
I've run out of tears to shed.
Yeah.
ano kumo otteiru todoitara shiawase to
We're chasing that cloud, thinking that we would be happy if we could reach it.
Aren't families great?
The happiest and the most painful,
everything is there.
That's precisely what it means for people to live.
So I lived.
ichiban hayaku kono saka nobotta mono gachi
The first one to climb this incline wins.
I lived together with her.
We were brash, ragged, strong, and weak.
I'm starting to make no sense.
No, I understand,
ichiban sukina ano basho mezashite
I'm aiming for the place I love the most.
so much that it almost hurts.
That's true.
You would understand, right?
Since we're adults.
I have faith now.
that I'm her mother.
Even though I might not be great, I'm her mother.
takusan no omoide ga aru hoka ni wa nani mo iranai gurai
There are so many memories; I almost don't need anything else.
I've decided to quit my current job and work at the neighbourhood daycare centre.
I want to live surrounded by many families from now on.
That's what I feel.
hitomi wo tojireba sugu ano umi no nioi
If I close my eyes, I immediately sense the smell of that ocean.
I'll visit occasionally.
That's good.
I'll be waiting.
The end of summer.
My vacation is ending too.
This summer vacation,
many fun things happened.
I had Mummy buy me
a dinosaur baby.
I'm glad.
mata natsu ga kuru giniro ni hikaru
Summer comes again; the shadows we reflect onto...
minamo ni utsusu futaribun no kage
...the surface of the water sparkles like silver.
Are you Sora?
You've gotten quite big.
Or are you a different crow?
I can't tell very well.
But if you're Sora, I'll have to scold you,
and say, "You're still here? She's not here anymore."
You have to go,
since you have wings.
The sky is a forever unreachable place for us humans, as we have no wings.
So you must fly!
For us, since we have no wings.
People's dreams and wishes, return them all to this sky!
Please!
That way, we'll be able to live peacefully.
That's what I feel.
It'll be nice if we can see each other again.
Well, best of luck to you!
Before I knew it, I was looking at the sky,
which had always been filled with a sad colour,
that endless blue that continues forever,
the girl who returned to that infinity,
the girl who is still all alone.
So I will go on a voyage to continue searching for her.
And someday, I will bring her back...
...to welcome a new beginning!
My child, listen carefully.
The story that I'm about to tell you is very important.
It is a long, long story of a journey that will be passed down from parent to child endlessly, starting now.
We continue to inherit the memories of the stars.
We see and hear every event that takes place on this planet and then pass it down, from mother to child.
The memories of the stars must be eternally happy.
When the sky is covered by hatred and war,
this planet will wail and grieve, and everything will return to the void.
Eventually reaching Apocalypse...
...is a fate that cannot be avoided.
But in the end, please give happy memories to the last child who bears the stars' memories.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just remembered the past.
The sun will set soon, eh?
Yeah.
Before it does, let's go check.
Check what?
What you wanted to check for a long time:
what is beyond this shoreline.
Did I say something like that?
You might not have said that,
but I had a feeling you were thinking that.
That's true, I want to go check.
If we do it now, we can find out what lies beyond there.
We're...
Let's go, shall we?
Yup.
To them, cruel days,
and to us, a beginning.
Goodbye.
The End
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
Intruding while your master is changing is the epitome of disloyalty!
"You are forbidden to commit murder," was it?
Do you really think I'll keep that vow?
Ryuuya-dono...
Um...
Summer Special