Then, perhaps, by my hands...
Hey, Kano.
Misuzu!
Kano!
Piko.
Pikopiko.
Piko pikopikopiko piko.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
That imprint might remain for a while.
I've caused you trouble.
I apologise, Kunisaki-san, Kamio-san.
Oh, not at all.
We don't mind.
It happened when Kano was still small.
Episode 4
It was the first summer after our mother died.
Look, look!
Onee-chan, balloons!
[Store sign: Balloons]
There, there!
Hey, hey, if I buy that, will I able to fly in the sky?
If a person could float upward with just one balloon, that yatai would be flying in the sky by now.
Hm, I see.
Onee-chan, you're so smart!
But that means that I can fly in the sky if I have lots of balloons, right?
Well, yes, you might be able to fly.
But we can only afford one.
If it's one balloon, we'll just have to blow it up really big!
If we do that, it'll be able to pick up much heavier things!
We won't be able to buy anything else.
Okay!
Here.
Wow, thank you, Onee-chan!
Ah!
Kano wanted to fly in the sky,
because she believed that she could see her mother there.
I told her that her mother was in the sky and that she was watching over her daughter.
Father and I couldn't tell her...
...that her mother was no longer anywhere.
Oh.
Kano!
What happened afterwards?
Nothing in particular happened.
Who's playing here?
We returned the feather to where we found it and went home together.
So I can't go to where Mummy is anymore?
Kano began to act strangely from the next day on.
She started to fear bright lights, to unconsciously wander around outside, and to mumble meaningless words to herself.
One night, Kano was gone before I realised.
After I quickly looked for her, I found her in this examination room, pressing a scalpel against her own wrist.
We treated it quickly, so it didn't become critical,
but at that time, I thought it wasn't Kano.
I thought that someone else was pretending to be Kano.
Was it a case of multiple personalities?
It might have been.
This is a mysterious bandanna.
If you keep wearing it until you're an adult, you'll be able to use magic.
So, no matter what happens, never take it off.
I see.
So you were the one who gave Kano the bandanna.
My childish heart thought that if she ever tried to unconsciously cut her wrist, she'd see the bandanna and come to her senses.
Kano doesn't remember it much.
There was never such a thing as magic.
I decided to follow in my father's footsteps.
I felt that I'd be able to cure Kano's disease someday if I became a doctor.
What was the feather that Kano touched?
I don't know.
It's apparently something in the shrine passed down from long ago; even the caretaker doesn't know the specifics.
Perhaps it's the curse of that feather.
As a doctor, I can't accept that as the reason.
However, there's a chance that the feather was the psychological trigger that caused the disease.
Back then, Kano bore a heavy burden in her heart after losing her mother.
That was probably the root cause.
Are you going to Kirishima-san's place today too?
Yeah.
After all, I have my part-time job there.
Maybe I'll visit her later.
Do that.
Aren't you glad that you made a new friend?
Last night, I saw another dream.
Eh?
A dream of flying in the sky.
In that dream, I was travelling further and further back in time.
I was grieving far above the clouds.
Grieving?
As usual, my body was soaring in the sky,
but I was overwhelmed by sadness.
Why did I, enclosed by the beautiful, comforting wind, feel so sad?
It was only a dream, right?
It has nothing to do with you.
Yes.
If you aren't smiling, I feel...
Eh?
Just smile.
V!
There's nothing here...
Found it!
What are you doing?
Yukito Kunisaki.
Why are you here?
That's my line.
Are you doing that to collect garbage or something?
Shut up.
Collecting things in places like this is my hobby.
That's the most pathetic hobby ever.
Leave me alone!
Jeez.
You get to hang around every day. You're in a really enviable position.
You're pretty much like that yourself, right?
I have a proper job.
Even now, I'm going to my part-time job to work hard.
Oi.
Hm?
Bathroom?
No, look there.
Hm?
That's...
Is that by any chance, Tohno's mum?
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Minagi seems sad.
Eh?
Hey, call her.
I think she's lonely being by herself.
That's true.
Let's try giving her a call.
Tohno!
Kunisaki-san.
What happened?
What brings you here?
Nothing in particular.
I was just taking a walk with Michiru.
Oh...
Huh?
Where'd she go?
You were with Michiru?
Yeah, I was with her.
Did Michiru say anything about the person who was with me just now?
No.
She didn't say anything in particular.
I see.
If that's the case, it's all right.
That person is your mum, right?
Eh?
I once helped her with a cart of grocery.
Come to think of it, the two of you are rather similar.
I am a fragment of that person's dream.
Huh?
Don't run away, Potato.
Here, I'll scrub you.
You seem to be in high spirits.
Ah, good morning, Yukito-kun.
I'm sorry. It seems that I caused you trouble yesterday too.
It was nothing much.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, you came, Kunisaki-kun.
There's lots of work to do today too.
Is Kano-san napping?
Yes.
I told her to rest, in part because of what happened yesterday.
It's about time for her to wake up.
I'll check up on her.
Kano?
Huh?
I'm writing this because I think that you'll believe me.
I've finally decided to go to the sky.
I have a feeling that if I do that, everyone can be happy.
I feel that I can meet the girl you're searching for too.
I don't know when it'll be, but I'll definitely bring that person.
I'll be grateful if you can help my sister until I return.
She's actually really pushing herself.
P.S. I'm really sorry for the bruise on your neck.
Oh.
Piko pikopikopikopiko.
Piko piko. Piko!
Kano!
Hold on, Kano!
There are no external injuries.
Then what about the blood?
There's no trace of bleeding.
It doesn't seem to be life-threatening, but what exactly happened?
Maybe she tried to go to the sky from here.
Oh?
What's this?
Oh!
What's wrong, Yukito-san?
Somehow, my emotions are acting up,
like I'm nostalgic... or sad.
Please lay Kano down.
Kunisaki-kun.
My name is Shiraho.
Please listen to my story.
I remember that the autumn was so beautiful.
My husband and I had our first child.
At birth, there was a bruise on that child's right wrist.
The villagers said it was ominous, but we never paid them any heed.
When Yakumo cried, I sang him a lullaby that I had learned from my mother.
Yakumo, who would always stop crying, acted differently one day.
I felt that the feather was an amulet that God had given to us.
Take them away!
A war started, and my husband, like many others, didn't return.
Did someone here pick up a shining feather?!
Feathers are soiled, so if you've touched one, show yourself and confess!
That night, I fled from the village.
And so, I arrived at this village.
The chief priest of the shrine was very kind towards us strangers.
I felt that I could start a new life with Yakumo in this peaceful village.
However, that summer, an epidemic spread in the village, killing many people.
Chief Priest, how is this child's condition?
The worst is over.
His fever will come down in time.
However, the people of the village believe that you two brought about the epidemic.
No!
It was a mistake to invite the two of you here.
Here, we worship the Miko-gami.
The Miko-gami gives a sign to those who bring disasters.
If the villagers hear of this child's bruise, they will clamour for his sacrifice.
You're telling me to sacrifice him?!
In this land, we have averted disasters by doing that.
This child is my life!
He's the one treasure that my husband left me!
Don't resist.
If you do, you will be killed too.
Then perhaps...
by my hands...
I can't!
I can't do it!
What mother would kill her own child?!
Even if that child will destroy the world, what mother can bear killing her own child?!
I will take his place.
Please, somehow, save this child, just this child.
Don't be rash!
Mummy?
Where's Mummy?
I'm right here.
Mummy!
Is there something you want to eat?
I'm already full.
Is there something you want?
No.
Um... I'll go home now,
because Onee-chan is waiting.
Potato too.
As well as a new friend that I've made.
Really?
He says that he's searching for a girl in the sky.
I felt that it'd be nice if I were that girl.
If it's painful, you can always come with me, you know.
Um, Mummy?
Thank you.
I don't remember you very well,
and I might have cut short your life,
but...
Thank you for giving birth to me!
I just wanted to say that.
Kano,
you don't have wings,
so be happy down there.
kono ko no kawaisa kagirinaya
この子の可愛さ限りなや
Limitless are the ways this child is dear,
ten ni tatoeba hoshi no kazu
天に例えば星の数
more so than the number of stars in the heavens,
yama de wa ki no kazu kaya no kazu
山では木の数かやの数
more so than the number of trees, the number of grass blades.
obana karukaya hagi kikyou
おばなかるかやはぎききょう
Flowering grass, bush clover and bellflowers...
nanakusa chigusa no kazu yori mo
七草千草の数よりも
More precious than all the flowers
daijina kono ko ga nennesuru
大事なこの子がねんねする
is my sleeping child.
Just now...
Kamio-san, you saw it too?
Yes.
Are you awake now?
Kano.
Yukito-kun.
Onee-chan.
Kano!
Pika!
So, what was that feather?
Who knows?
Onee-chan, I met Mummy.
Yes, I was watching.
I couldn't go to where she was, but I was able to properly thank her, just as Yukito-kun told me to.
It's all thanks to Yukito-kun.
No, you're mistaken.
That was your magic.
Yup.
Let it drift into the sky for you.
Okay.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
Bubbles are pretty.
They're empty, just like the sky.
I'm really a bother, so I'm always playing by myself.
Did I do something bad?
My mother lost a vent for her feelings, so she chose to continue watching a dream.
Is there a use for wings that cannot fly?
Episode 5