What exactly happened?
I was surprised because all of a sudden, you were collapsed on the floor.
I suddenly felt dizzy and tripped.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
A slight anaemia, perhaps?
What now? Do you want to go to the hospital?
No, I'm fine.
I think I'll get better if I rest.
Supplemental classes started already.
It won't matter if you miss one class, right?
Sleep today.
Yes.
Yukito-san, what about your part-time job?
I'll take today off.
I went to school with Yukito-san.
I played with Yukito-san.
A cicada flew into Yukito-san's breakfast.
I went to the train station with Yukito-san.
I went to the shrine with Yukito-san.
Don't read someone else's diary.
You don't have anything else to write about?
That diary is my masterpiece.
Well, to put it bluntly, you have no talent for keeping diaries.
So from now on, write about what you want to do, not what you did.
But that's... not a diary.
No, that's a diary.
I'll make everything you write about come true.
I want to go to the ocean with you,
because I've never gone down to the beach.
I want to dig in the sand and pick up pretty shells.
Jeez...
We see the ocean all the time, right?
Gao.
Ouch.
All right.
Eh?
We'll go the ocean together.
Yes.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
That child said that she wanted to go to the ocean,
but I couldn't take her.
Episode 7
Misuzu collapsed?
Yeah.
She hasn't recovered yet.
She's resting in her room right now.
Please see her.
She'll only get worse if I show her my alcohol-stenched face.
Forget that; I bought sushi.
Let's have a great time together!
That hurt me a LOT.
Why did you take Misuzu in?
Huh?
Why did you end up taking Misuzu in?!
Oh, she told you about it?
I didn't take her in; she was pushed onto me,
though I said that I didn't want her.
That's why she isn't getting the love she needs!
Realise it!
You're the only parent she has!
That girl has an attack when she becomes friends with someone.
We distanced ourselves.
That's why we can live together.
What is a parent-child relationship?
I'm not a real parent, so I don't know very well.
Yuck, wrong sushi.
The girl dreams.
First, it's a dream of the skies.
The dream gradually goes back in time.
It starts to eat away at the girl.
She begins to feel a pain that shouldn't be there, and gradually, the girl begins to forget everything.
She begins to forget even her most precious friend,
and in the morning after dreaming her last dream, the girl will die.
She is always alone.
If she becomes close to another, both will become sick.
Neither of them will survive.
So the girl said,
"Leave me."
She was a very kind and strong girl.
That's why I was able to live.
But she...
In the sky, there is a girl with wings.
She is always alone and eventually disappears, unable to become an adult.
She repeats such a sad dream.
You're going on a trip?!
That's right. I'll drift around, travelling alone.
A hot springs tour.
What are you thinking?!
What are you going to do about Misuzu?!
I'm leaving her in your hands.
If you don't get too close to her, those attacks won't happen that easily, right?
Wait!
Misuzu is dreaming right now.
That dream is making Misuzu behave like this.
Huh?
I remembered a story I heard from my mum.
Mum had met a girl with the same kind of sickness before.
After a while, Misuzu will begin to forget about me and about you too.
Then, after seeing her final dream, she'll probably die.
You know, there are some jokes that just can't be told.
It's not a joke.
Misuzu is...
Move.
Hey!
I'm coming in.
Oh, you were awake?
Yes.
I just woke up.
I heard Mummy's voice.
Yeah, she'll be out for a while.
Is that so?
I love Mummy.
Let's go to the ocean.
Take your time; don't push yourself.
Okay.
Oh, a crow.
Misuzu.
Hey, are you all right?
Yes.
I'm fine.
V!
Even though I've walked this way many times, was the ocean always this far?
What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
I... again...
Those attacks again?
I'm sorry!
It'll get better soon... so...
the ocean... tomorrow, instead...
Are you better now?
Yes.
Hey.
Hmm?
I had a dream again last night.
This time, it was a fun dream.
Even though it was night-time, the sky was bright.
There was probably a festival.
I was watching from far away.
I see.
Hey, Yukito-san.
What is it?
The person you're looking for and my dreams are connected, right?
Who knows.
They could be unrelated.
Will you listen to the answer I found after much thought?
My dreams represent my other self,
and that girl is suffering right now.
I'll try my best and dream,
because I might be able to understand her that way.
If I do that, I might be able to save that girl.
Yukito-san, it's not by coincidence that I started seeing these dreams, right?
I felt that this year's summer was special.
I thought that I would do my best to make a friend.
Then I met you and started seeing those dreams.
It's probably all connected, right?
That's why I want to try my hardest.
I want to make this summer the happiest because it's the summer that I met you.
Hey.
I'm all right now.
I'm feeling better too.
Misuzu!
Huh?
What happened?
My feet won't move.
It might be best to call Hijiri,
or perhaps a big hospital.
No.
A doctor probably won't be able to heal it.
Yukito-san, you understand too, right?
My dreams are doing this to me.
No way...
I had a dream last night too.
A dream of travelling.
Travelling?
I was travelling to find something.
I walked in the forest for days and days.
It was hard, but I persevered,
because a precious person was by my side.
A precious person?
I know that as I dream, I gradually weaken until finally I... like the girl in the sky...
Idiot!
As if something like that could happen!
I got scolded.
You don't have to think about your other self.
Just worry about recovering for now.
Yes.
Misuzu-chin is a strong girl.
Yukito-san!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
There can't be nothing wrong with a face like that.
My face was like this to start with.
Misuzu, go back to bed.
I can't leave you by yourself.
I'm fine.
Don't make me worry about you.
Okay.
What's with... this scar?
It hurts!
Misuzu, hang on.
Misuzu.
I'm fine.
I'll be better soon, so stay by my side...
But if I'm nearby...
It's all right; stay by my side.
Why does everyone... leaving just me...
How are you feeling?
I'm fine now.
What about you, Yukito-san?
There's nothing wrong with me.
What now?
Do you want to call Hijiri after all?
Or Kano?
Minagi... is out of town.
Maybe someone from your class?
No.
It's all right.
I don't want to cause them trouble.
Don't lie.
You want friends, right?
You don't want to be alone, right?
I just want you to be here.
Your being here is enough for me.
Does that trouble you?
Idiot!
I want to go to the ocean with you.
We're going to play at the beach.
We're going to race, throw water at each other, and when we're done, part saying, "See you tomorrow!"
But for now, I'll hold back.
That way, I'll be happier when I do go to the ocean.
Misuzu-chin, fight!
Misuzu.
Yes?
I plan on leaving soon.
Eh?
If I stay with you any longer, neither of us will live.
So I've decided to run away from you.
I'll leave this town and go to a place where I will never see you again.
By yourself?
Yeah.
We've become... too close.
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
It can't be helped, right?
I really should have just played by myself like this.
Maybe.
It was fun.
This summer vacation.
This summer vacation that I spent with you.
I feel the same way.
Really?
Yeah.
There are no more buses?
Yukito-san.
You see, in my dream this morning,
I was locked up all alone.
I was sad.
I was waiting for a long time for someone to let me out.
I... I... want to go with you.
With you!
Is there any way for me to follow you?
It's not that I want to leave this place.
I have to distance myself from you.
If I leave you, you should recover.
That's why I can't stay by your side.
I see.
That's right.
I'm sorry for saying stupid things again.
No.
Then...
Byebye.
Take care.
Hang in there.
Even if you're alone, hang in there.
Yes.
I'll try my best even if I'm alone.
I'm a strong girl.
Good.
See you.
Misuzu...
What are you feeling now, Yukito?
Do you feel that you want the people who watch to laugh?
If that's not the case, it won't move.
The doll moves not just because of the wish to make it move but also because of the wish beyond that.
Good job.
That child said, "I want to go to the ocean."
But I couldn't take her.
Yukito.
This time, finally, I want you to save her.
Inside this doll, there are wishes that weren't granted.
My mother and my mother's mother, before losing their strength, sealed their powers inside this doll.
For the eventual day when someone will release their wishes.
So, I will become one of those wishes.
It is up to you how you will use this.
You can forget about the girl who lives in the sky.
However, Yukito...
In a town somewhere, you will probably meet a girl.
If you wish to save her no matter what, put your heart into the doll,
because I am with you.
Put my heart... in the doll?
This guy's been weird like this for a while.
Maybe he's sick from the heat.
L-Let me go.
Help me, please.
Eh?
I want you to watch this and tell me how to make it more fun and how to make more people laugh.
Wow, it's great.
How mysterious.
But it's not that fun.
Yeah.
Why don't you try doing more instead of just making it walk around?
Make it be part of a story.
Make it dance or something.
D-Dance?
It has to be more novel.
Wow.
That was great!
That performance was fun!
It was fun and cute!
Is that so?
Thanks for staying with me all this time.
Well then, good luck!
See you!
Misuzu, I'm back.
I won't go anywhere anymore.
I'll stay with you and continue to make you laugh.
Yukito-san...
I learned some tricks.
They're definitely fun, so watch carefully.
Misuzu!
Please watch!
Please laugh!
Why didn't I notice until now?
I was just happy being by your side and seeing you smile.
If I just did that, I was happy.
I won't go anywhere anymore!
Laugh by my side.
Okay, Misuzu?
Yukito,
you must remember now...
...what you must do...
I... I want to be by Misuzu's side.
If I can, I would relive life from when we first met.
And this time...
with Misuzu... forever...
Why is it?
I thought I couldn't get up anymore...
Yukito-san?
Where did you go?
You came back, right?
Hey, I'm healthy again.
I think I can try my hardest again.
Hey, Yukito-san?
SEIREKI: YEAR FIVE
Ouch ouch ouch...
You... Why are you in such a place?
If you have the leisure to open your mouth, please hurry and move!
You... You're a face I'm not acquainted with.
[Note: Lower Eighth Level]
Shou Hachii Ge,
Daisakan of Saemon, Ryuuya.
And you... Where did you fall from?
You do not know my name?
Dunno.
We just met.
Indeed.
Surprisingly, I'm still somewhat unknown.
I'm Kanna.
What a coincidence.
The winged person I was ordered to protect is also named Kanna.
Oh, that's truly a coincidence.
Yeah, really.
You idiot!
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
When you say "winged person", you mean the gods' messengers, right?
They are beings who can speak directly to the gods, can battle against famines and epidemics, and can purify and pray.
Family means to huddle together.
I want to see him.
I had never felt that being alone would be this painful.
Episode 8