The day before summer vacation
My name is Misuzu.
Kamio Misuzu.
We need to give you a name too.
That guy was on the embankment when we were going home from school, right?
A puppet show like that isn't popular nowadays.
Oh, I'm hungry.
I know!
Sora.
Let's name you Sora.
That's the place where I always gaze at the sky.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Hello.
He doesn't seem to be sick.
It feels like we're friends when we're like this.
The sunset is pretty, isn't it?
I wish I could play like that with someone too.
Oh.
Byebye!
Episode 10
What's that black thing?!
He followed me.
It seems he's too small and can't fly.
It's amazing a thing like this became your friend.
I gave it a name, Sora.
We're going to live together.
Rejected.
Wah, that was fast.
If you want a pet, get a cat or a dog.
I'll be depressed if something like this wanders around the house.
Don't be like that.
It's cute.
See?
Say hello to Mummy.
My eyes!
Mummy was really angry, wasn't she?
I'll let you stay in my room secretly for tonight.
Let's both apologise to Mummy tomorrow, okay?
Summer vacation starts tomorrow.
I've been thinking of asking someone in my class this year.
But will they play with me?
Let's try practising it a bit.
Um...
I want you to play with me during summer vacation.
Oh, it has to be in the afternoon though because I have supplemental classes.
We'll swim in the ocean, play cards, play with fireworks, and also do homework together, okay?
It's easy for me since I'm just copying all the time.
Just kidding.
I'll do my best too.
Yes.
I'm starting to feel confident.
I'll be back at noon, so play by yourself until then, okay?
You can't go too far away though.
Piko?
Piko!
Piko piko!
Look, a crow!
It really is one.
It's all black.
Ew, it's disgusting!
Eh? It's cute.
Ah! It came over here!
Run!
Huh?
It's a crow!
Where did you come from?
Oh, don't worry.
I won't bully you or anything.
Oh, no, don't do that!
I can't take it off yet.
That's because I'll be able to use magic if I take it off once I become an adult.
There are cars and things on the road, so be careful.
See you!
Hey, hey, let's go to the ocean.
Sure, sure!
My swimsuit this year is really revealing!
Eh?!
I mustn't cry.
Hold it back. Hold it back.
Sora, it seems I'll be alone this summer too.
I couldn't find anyone to play with.
Because everyone knows that I'm not a normal child.
But I'll do something really fun by myself.
I'm going to make my free assignment a diary and write down everything that was fun.
So... So I'm all right.
It's the person from yesterday.
Hey, I don't want to be all alone after all.
I don't want to be the only one all alone in the long summer vacation.
So I'll try talking to that person.
If he seems nice, I'll try asking him to play with me.
Smile. Smile. Act natural.
Ramen Set!
Hello.
Are you alone?
What do you mean?!
Why are there more?!
More?!
MORE?!
You made me say it three times.
That just means that it was that shocking.
But Mummy...
Rejected.
That's not how you said it would be.
Well, you seem to have guts, and I don't dislike that part of you.
That's right. Yukito-san is a very good person.
I understand.
I'll let him stay.
Serious?
Very serious, not just seriously serious.
Did he say Kunisaki Yukito?
He seems to be friendly towards Misuzu, but she hasn't had those attacks yet.
He might be able to become Misuzu's friend.
She hasn't had a friend all this time because of her illness.
He doesn't seem to be a bad guy, so I want to try betting on him.
Don't you have any other ones?
The rest are too small.
Mm, smells nice.
Sora?
Mummy and Yukito-san have work, and I have supplemental classes.
Watch the house, okay?
Are they out?
I bought this; now what should I do?
What are you doing in a place like this?
It's me.
Perfect timing.
Hop on.
There's going to be a festival here soon.
The tenth summer festival since that time.
I still remember it well after all this time.
She sat in front of where they were selling chicks and talked to them for a long time,
saying "Gao! Gao!"
That girl thought that if she brought a chick up, it would become a dinosaur.
Even if one did raise a chick that was brought at a fair, there's no way it would grow up.
I tried to take her hand and drag her home.
And then...
She was raised an obedient girl, but she just stared at me
and said "I want this" really longingly, just that one time.
Misuzu wasn't wanted at birth.
She's the child of two people who weren't even married, born amidst many fights.
My older sister died, leaving him and the child.
The man, who was left, pushed his own daughter onto me.
It was really troublesome.
I somehow lived on believing that one of these days, that man will return for his daughter.
But you know, spending long hours with Misuzu,
who is easily flustered and acts clumsily,
but always laughs and forgets that, made me laugh too.
Despite all that, I'm not her parent.
That man might come any day to take her away.
Then, I'll have no choice but to revert to my solitary existence.
I maintained my own way of life so that I won't be too miserable when we eventually part.
That's why I haven't ever given her a present, not even on her birthday.
I pretended to forget each year.
I debated what to do this year too, but...
I won't after all.
It's too late to become a real family now.
I remember definitely seeing that person and this scene somewhere before.
But...
When?
Where?
I just can't remember.
Wah, the cicadas came in from the ventilation fan again!
Wah, the soy sauce container fell!
Wah, the salad oil spilled!
Yukito-san's bacon egg is all ruined.
Yukito-san, is it good?
Yeah.
Really?
It doesn't taste like cicadas?
What do you mean by that?!
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
G-Gao.
Hey.
Where are you going?
What a weird crow.
I wish that Saika-oneechan gets better.
Mummy?
Is there really a god?
Of course there is.
God is watching over Saika and Maika right now.
He will definitely grant your wish.
Mummy,
this is God.
It was walking by itself!
It looks like it's brand new.
Let's leave it here,
because this is God's house.
Yes.
Oh.
Are you alone?
You aren't running away.
You're smart.
If you don't have a home, will you come to the station with me?
I think you can definitely become good friends with Michiru.
You can also eat as much food as you want.
Ultra-happy.
I see. So you have somewhere to return to.
Please do your best,
so that one day, you can fly with those wings.
Try thinking about the one who has to be called to school each time you have an attack.
I'm sorry.
You're fine when you're with that freeloader, right?
I thought that you had got better.
Well, I'm returning to work, okay?
I'm sorry for causing you trouble.
Mummy was angry, wasn't she?
But you know, she came to school so quickly.
It's always like that.
Yukito-san is probably waiting.
I wonder if he's worrying.
I have to be as natural as I can.
I'm going to make it seem like I was just careless and forgot to meet him,
because I want Yukito-san to think I'm a normal girl.
Misuzu.
I'm home.
I'm hooome!
Misuzu suddenly...
I know.
Sora,
apparently Yukito-san left.
I wanted to spend more time with him.
But he said he'll walk me to and from school like before,
so I just have to live with that, right?
I can still see him every day from now on, right?
Ow!
I wonder what's wrong.
These days, my back sometimes hurts...
Why did you end up taking Misuzu in?!
That's why she isn't getting the love she needs!
Realise it!
You're the only parent she has!
He didn't have to be so harsh.
I've known that for a long time, even without being told.
How much longer do I have to live like this?
Fearing she might disappear any day and not giving her any presents even on her birthday...
I've decided.
I'll make her my child.
I'll ride into Tachibana's house and negotiate!
That's right. I'll drift around, travelling alone on a hot springs tour.
What are you thinking?!
What are you going to do about Misuzu?!
Misuzu, I'm going.
If I stay with you any longer, neither of us will be saved,
so I've decided to distance myself from you.
Well, it can't be helped.
It can't be helped, right?
It was fun spending the summer vacation with you.
I feel the same way.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm going now.
Yes.
Byebye, Yukito-san.
He left.
I'll be all alone.
I'll really be alone.
I can't do my best anymore if I'm alone.
What should I do?
I have a good idea.
I should go on a voyage too.
If I do that, I won't have to part with Yukito-san.
It's a good idea.
It's not that I want to leave this house.
I have to distance myself from you.
Hang in there.
Even if you're alone, hang in there.
Yes.
I'll try my best, even if I'm alone.
I'm a strong girl.
All right.
See you.
I'm all alone now,
really all alone.
Yukito-san.
Mummy.
It hurts.
I was all alone until now.
It'll be the same starting tomorrow.
In the end, even if I try my best, I just cause other people trouble, and nothing good ever happens.
I should have kept on giving up like before,
without loving anyone!
I'll go to sleep.
I don't care if I never wake up.
I've finally realised.
I was happy, just being by your side and seeing you smile.
Why is it?
I thought I couldn't get up anymore.
Yukito-san?
Where did you go?
You came back, right?
That's right.
I remember.
I was once a human,
a human called Kunisaki Yukito,
and I was by Misuzu's side.
Hey, I'm healthy again.
I think I can try my hardest again.
Hey, Yukito-san?
Misuzu.
I'm here.
Right here.
Yukito-san!
Misuzu.
Yukito-san.
Yukito-san!
Misuzu.
I'll try my best.
I'll try my best, okay?
So... So don't go anywhere anymore. Stay by my side forever.
Yukito-san.
It's all right.
You're a strong girl, so you'll be able to reach, for sure,
a goal no one has ever been able to reach.
You can reach it.
I don't want you to go anywhere.
I don't want that.
I'll be by your side forever.
I'll never forget you.
I'll be with you.
Yukito-san?
Yukito-san!
My mind is starting to blur again.
But Misuzu, I'm with you.
I'll be with you forever.
Yukito-san, wait!
Don't go.
Let's try our best, Misuzu.
Until we reach our goal, let's try our best, okay, Misuzu?
Yes.
I'll do my best.
Let's do our best, Yukito-san.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
Where should I cut it to?
I'll leave it up to you, Mummy.
Mum?
Yes, it's me.
Mum went far away.
Misuzu!
I'm your dad.
No!
If she says at that time that she doesn't want to be with me anymore, then I won't mind!
Gao.
Episode 11