Good morning.
Why are you...
Yes?
Oh, right, so you've been staying here since last night.
Breakfast is ready.
You brought all this from your house?
Yes.
Maybe you're more suited to travelling than I am.
Minagi!
Welcome home!
Michiru.
I was worried because you didn't come yesterday.
I'm really glad that I wished.
Wished?
Yup.
I wished upon the stardust that you would come back.
Really?
All right. Breakfast, breakfast!
I'll eat too.
Hey, show some restraint!
What did you say?!
Don't be so stingy!
I'm not stingy!
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Why didn't you wait for me this morning?
I went to pick you up.
Mm, I had a little errand.
I'm sorry.
Well, it's okay.
Do you still have those dreams?
Yes.
Last night, it was a dream of a forest at night.
I was talking to someone in the forest.
Forest?
With who?
I don't know, but there was someone snuggled beside me.
I asked that person, "What's an ocean?"
Then, that person told me lots about the ocean.
It was really fun just talking.
It was so fun that I wanted to wrap up the words and store them forever.
If it was that fun, sleep forever.
G-Gao.
Ouch.
Episode 6
A fan, a fan!
Kunisaki-san.
Welcome back!
I'm back.
You must be tired.
How did your puppet show go?
Um... Well... Not good!
What?
Kunisaki Yukito, you good-for-nothing!
What was that for?!
Shut up!
Someone who eats for free shouldn't talk so conceitedly!
Whaaaaaaat did you say?
Playing, eating, and sleeping...
She's in a really enviable situation.
Last night, I dreamed about my father.
Of your dad?
Long ago, I often sat here, watching the stars with my father.
It was a dream of those times.
Minagi.
In each and every star, there exists a god watching over us.
They also clean the souls of those who watch the stars.
A short time after that, my father left.
After my younger sister died, my father and mother started to quarrel.
Where is your father now?
He married another woman in a faraway town.
When we parted, he gave me this.
Hey, don't you have to work now?
I'm taking a short rest.
Hey, Minagi has run away from home now, right?
Huh?
Even if you try to hide it, I can tell, because I'm a friend.
It's not good being like this, after all.
Minagi has to wake up from her dream now.
What do you mean by that?
I'm going home now, okay?
See you!
Piko.
Piko pika.
Hey!
Piko!
See you later.
Piko...
I'm sorry for having caused you trouble.
Not at all. Please don't hesitate to come again if something happens.
I won't.
She's starting to remember?
Yeah.
She said she lost something important.
She came to receive an examination because of that?
I replied that she would eventually remember when she found it.
The rest is up to Minagi-san's feelings.
Welcome back.
Is something wrong?
I've... decided to leave this town.
What?
I've stayed here way too long;
I think it's time for me to go.
I... see.
Will you come with me, Tohno?
Eh?
I want to show you the world, the real world, not a dream world.
The world?
Let's go together to discover that world.
I'm ready.
All right. Let's go.
Um...
Kunisaki-san.
Before we go,
I want to leave a message for Michiru.
Just follow me.
Oh boy.
We've finally arrived.
Why?
Michiru said that she doesn't want to see a sad-looking Minagi.
Michiru said...
From here on, decide by your own will what you do.
If you want, you can really go on a journey with me.
I'll take you... to some other place.
The choice is yours.
Let your own will decide for you.
Mummy?
Minagi...
Mummy!
The stars are brilliant today too!
Yeah.
Do you think that Minagi is watching the stars too?
Yeah, probably with her mum.
I... have to go home now.
Yeah, it's quite late.
If you want, I'll walk you home.
Where do you live?
I have... a home to return to.
Michiru?
In the sky, there's a really sad-looking girl.
Girl?
In the sky?
That girl always sees just sad dreams and has nothing else.
She can't become happy, so she can do nothing but see sad dreams.
On her back, there are wounded feathers,
feathers with a really mysterious power.
They're packed with the memories of many people.
I had her share one of them with me,
because there was someone I wanted to meet and comfort.
Also, I thought that if that person became happy, the girl who lives in the sky could become happy too.
I see.
Humans can't live without memories, you know.
Still, they can't live on memories alone.
You have to awaken from your dreams eventually.
Because dreams you don't awaken from eventually become sadness.
So I'm going to go return the feather.
It's sad to say goodbye to everyone, but because I'm just a dream...
Because stars have to disappear when the sun rises...
Michiru, you're...
I'm a fragment of a dream.
My being here is just a dream.
But you know, it was a really fun dream.
I was really happy.
I...
The real Michiru...
wasn't allowed to be born into this world.
I met Michiru for the first time... at that station.
Every day, I went to pick up my father at the station, even after he left.
Father had already quit his job, but there was nothing else I could do.
Was it around then that your mother began to call you Michiru?
Yes.
But my mother laughed when I acted as Michiru, so...
Hijiri said that you stopped smiling as much from then on.
It was an afternoon in summer, after a rain shower had ended.
I felt that I had met her before.
I felt that she was always nearby.
My name is Michiru!
I'm...
I'm... Minagi.
Everything started from my sin.
Sin?
If I hadn't wished for a younger sister, no one would have had to dream.
I might even hurt Michiru now too.
Even then, I want to let someone very important catch at least one glimpse of her.
Hey, wait!
Kei-chan, if you don't hurry, we won't get places for the fireworks competition.
I know, but wait for me!
Huh? I fell asleep?
You were probably tired from playing all day.
You're hungry, right?
Will you eat dinner at my house?
At your... house?
It's rare for my daughter to bring a friend home, so I made it with the utmost care.
Oh dear.
I haven't even asked about your name yet.
Um... my name?
Yes, name.
Can you tell me?
Tell her.
Is it okay?
U-Um...
My name is... Michiru!
Michiru?
Really?
So you're called Michiru?
U-Um...
I'm actually, really...
Really...
Michiru.
It's a really good name.
Eh?
This girl really loved hamburgers from when she was little too.
She always said that if she has a younger sister someday, she'd want her to eat Mummy's hamburgers.
Right, Minagi?
Now, Michiru-chan, the hamburgers will get cold, so eat up.
You love them too, right?
Yes.
Thanks for the food.
So, are they good?
Yes, they're really delicious!
I invented these hamburgers.
Here.
I taught Minagi how to make them.
Is it okay?
Yes.
I'll be very happy if you eat lots of them.
Thank you!
Goodbye,
Mother.
Then I'll hold on to this for you, okay?
Treat it with care, okay, Minagi?
Of course.
Michiru...
Michiru!
No, without even saying goodbye...
It's not loo late.
There should still be time,
because the stars aren't out yet.
Michiru is probably there.
Michiru!
Michiru.
It's dangerous.
It's dangerous there, so come over here.
I can't, because I have to go now.
It's been lots of fun up till now, so I have to go.
Don't make a face like that.
Minagi, you have to be smiling.
Or else I'll be sad.
Michiru...
I... was able to be myself thanks to you, Michiru.
If you leave, I probably won't be able to laugh ever again.
It's all right.
Minagi, you can laugh with people other than me now.
Hey, Minagi,
Kunisaki Yukito,
let's make a promise.
Promise?
The girl with wings continues to dream sad dreams above the sky.
I'll go back to where she is before you.
I'll take the fun memories you guys gave me to where that girl is.
So...
If you find her, I want you to tell her many more fun stories and free her from her sad dreams.
Yeah.
Minagi.
Minagi, always smile, okay?
Smile and say "bye bye," okay?
I can't say it.
I can't smile and say goodbye...
Minagi.
...because I won't be able to see you anymore!
It's all right.
Because even if you awaken from a dream, the memories will remain.
So smile.
Make your memories with me happy, forever,
because this is something that only you can do.
Minagi, it's a promise.
Yes.
Are you smiling now?
Really?
Yes.
Then keep smiling.
Continue to smile and say "bye bye."
Are you smiling, Michiru?
Yes.
Saying goodbye isn't painful?
No, it's not,
because I'm smiling.
Wouldn't it be nice if everyone could live smiling all the time?
The world would be full of many smiles, and everyone would be warm.
Minagi.
Michiru.
Bye bye.
Thank you, Michiru.
Hey, what's up?
You haven't run away from home again, have you?
A rice ticket?
It's a letter from my father.
He asks if I want to see him this summer vacation.
Surprisingly, it seems that I have a younger sister,
a girl born to my father and his current wife.
That girl... Her name is...
Truthfully, I was a little hesitant, but I've decided to go see her.
My mother recommended it too.
I see.
Tohno!
There is a meaning for wings that cannot fly!
It's a precious memory of when you once flew in the sky.
Right, Michiru?
You like... bubbles?
Yes.
I love them!
But but... I can't blow them well.
Then do you want me to teach you?
Really?
Yes.
Let's be friends.
I'm Minagi.
What's your name?
Um, um!
Misuzu!
I've come to pick you up.
[Sign: I'm working hard on my homework]
Hey, Misuzu!
Misuzu!
Hang on!
Misuzu?!
Wake up, Misuzu!
Misuzu!
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
Yukito-san.
It's not by coincidence that I started seeing dreams, right?
I felt that this year's summer was special.
I thought that I would do my best to make a friend.
Then, I met you and started seeing those dreams.
It's probably all connected, right?
So, I wanted to do my best.
I wanted to make this summer the happiest,
because it's the summer that I met you, Yukito-san.
Episode 7