My child, listen carefully.
The story that I'm about to tell you is very important.
It is a long, long story of a journey that will be passed down from parent to child endlessly, starting now.
I'm hungry.
Ah, I'm hungry.
That's all you've been saying.
You're so slow. Walk faster.
Hey, you guys!
Do you guys know of a menu item called "Ramen Set?"
I'm so famished right now.
There's nothing I want more than to eat some Ramen Set.
But...
Unfortunately, I have no money. So...
Come! It's the start of a fun puppet show!
You can pay after you watch.
What do you think? Isn't it great? Isn't it interesting? Isn't it fun?
What the heck is this?! What a dirty doll.
Uncool.
Can't it do anything else?
Hey, hey!
Kids are best when they're honest.
You can pay me without holding back, OK?
That's why we're telling you honestly that it's not cool.
There's no way we'll pay for something like this.
Are you stupid?
You guys!
Take that!
Run!
Wait, you guys!
It's so hot...
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
R-R-Ramen Set!
Episode 1
Hello!
Who is this person?
Are you alone?
It's hot, isn't it?
What? Why are you here? Money? I have no money.
Are you thirsty?
I'll buy you a drink.
Here!
You fell.
Gao!
Gooey Concentrated Peach Flavoured.
Why did you do that?
You're teasing me, aren't you?
That's not true.
This drink is good.
Will you go to the beach?
Why would I?
Because I want to play.
Huh?
Yesterday, the little kids were playing at the beach.
I thought it looked fun, and I wanted to play too...
Next to you as you slept.
Were you watching?
You've been sleeping since yesterday, right?
I poked you, trying to wake you,
but you didn't wake up.
I was so hungry that I couldn't move.
Where are you going?
To work.
Work? What kind of work?
Puppeteering.
It's gone!
Is it very important?
It's a tool of the trade.
It's hot, isn't it? That's enough. Go home.
Oh!
There it is!
Crow! Crow!
No! It's the other thing!
Aren't you glad?
Yeah, I'm glad. I owe you.
Now you can play with me.
What do you want?
Why have you been following me all this time?
Like I said, we're going to play at the beach.
We're going to race, throw water at each other...
And in the end, we'll say "See you tomorrow!"
...and go our separate ways.
That's almost like we're friends.
Yes, friends.
We're friends.
So you see...
I want to play.
We don't know each other's names yet.
My name is Kamio Misuzu. What's yours?
Kunisaki Yukito...
No, I mean I have work to do!
Since I'm hungry, I have to make money.
Oh! If that's the case...
I followed her blindly, lured by food.
Isn't eating together nice?
Are you normally alone?
Mummy comes home late, and I don't have a Daddy.
After you're done eating, let's play, okay?
No. If it gets late, I'll have trouble finding a place to stay.
You don't have a place to stay yet?
No. Though I'll probably be sleeping outside anyway.
Stay at my house!
You know, we just met today.
On top of that, I'm a person with a dubious background and an unknown history.
Would you normally let someone like that stay?
First things first, your mum won't allow it.
Mummy's a very sloppy person, so I don't think there'll be any problems.
But I guess I shouldn't be talking about my own mother like this.
But really, it's all right if you stay.
I'm tired; I have no energy to play.
It's all right if we play tomorrow.
It's summer vacation, so there's plenty of time.
No way.
Gao...
Hey, how do you think maths will help us?
Will quadratic functions be of any use in the future?
How should I know?
Anyway, why am I helping you with your homework?
Hey, your eyes are too close.
Yukito-san, you sound like Mummy.
Really?
Mummy's home.
Hey!
She ran into the shed on her bike.
Don't worry. It happens all the time.
Are you really sure it's OK for me to be here?
Yup, I'll convince her.
Rejected!
That's not how you said it would be.
There's no argument!
There's no way we can let such a young man stay.
Gao!
I thought I told you to stop that bad habit.
What relationship do you have with Misuzu?
CLASSMATE
Uh... her classmate.
Heh, you seem to be really old.
DON'T FALL FOR ME
Don't fall for me.
As if I would?!
Well, you seem to have guts, and I don't dislike that part of you.
That's right, Yukito-san is a very good person.
All right. He can stay.
You're serious?
Very serious, not just seriously serious.
However, there are two conditions!
You'll sleep in the shed.
And...
You'll join me in a drink.
And then, at the end, he said this:
"Perhaps the one who fell in love was me."
How's that! I win, right?
So I replied,
"The fish you don't catch is a mermaid."
How's that? That struck home, right?
How... did it end up like this?
Mummy's at her best.
Hey, freeloader, why're you looking so stale? Why don't you do something too?
My eeeeeyes!
Yukito-san!
Do something? What am I supposed to do?
It can be anything, like an erotic confession of love or a hidden talent.
I see. If that's the case.
Oh, that's the doll from before.
Oh! Wow, great.
I'm making money from this trick.
My mother also travelled with this vocation.
Is there no punch line to this?
Not good! You're not funny.
But isn't it great that it's not a trick?
As if that matters.
Even if I could see the strings, I'd like it better if it were more interesting.
Good night.
Ah! He's trying to leave.
It doesn't really matter that you don't have that kind of skill.
Just drown the sorrow with some drinks!
I'm Haruko, Kamio Haruko.
Can I get another, ma'am?
Didn't I tell you my name so that you wouldn't call me that?!
You're such an insensitive man.
So... Are you a runaway?
I'm on a journey.
Are you chasing a goal or a dream?
I guess.
You're so young.
More so than you.
You're quite an amusing person.
Really?
I may look like this, but I do think that I have an eye for judging men.
I can let you stay for a while,
but I have a favour to ask.
Can you look after this girl?
Huh?
You've seen her reckless side, right?
She's impulsive, and if she sees something interesting, she'll be attracted to it like a bee to honey.
So I'm a babysitter?
Also, can you stop her habit of saying that phrase?
“Gao!” is what she says when she's troubled or about to cry, right?
Yeah...
That's an imitation of a dinosaur.
She loves dinosaurs, and it's a phrase that she has been using since she was young.
She's still a child, this girl.
What are you doing? Isn't it summer vacation?
Actually, I have supplemental classes.
Haruko left already.
Yes, she wakes up early every day.
It's the first time in a while that I've eaten breakfast with someone.
Yukito-san, what will you do today?
For now, I'll walk you to school. Haruko asked me to do it.
She said to watch out so that you don't do anything stupid.
She still doesn't trust me.
Gao!
I'm done! This is a map of the town.
That was fast.
This map shows where many people congregate.
It'll be of use for your work, right?
Yeah, it'll help.
Oh, I'm going to be late.
Misuzu-chin is in a pinch!
I'll come to pick you up later. We'll meet here.
Okay!
V!
Japanese use
these, right?
It's the ocean!
Delicious!
I'm starving.
Munch munch
What... is this?
Is this the world of her heart?
Piko!
What are you?!
Pikopiko!
Are you this town's local legendary being?
Pikopikopiko!
If that's the case, if I do it a favour, like in those fairy tales,
maybe it'll give me something in return.
Pikopikopiko!
Okay, come over here. I'll show you something nice.
Piko!
Pikopiko!
Piko! Piko!
What do you think?
Isn't it such a wonderful act that it makes you feel like giving me something in return?
Piko! Piko!
Pikopiko!
PIKO!
Hey!
Piko!
Hold it!
Wait!
Piko! Piko! Piko!
Piko!
Pikopiko!
Piko! Piko!
Give me a break, you evil extraterrestrial creature.
Piko... Piko...
Piko!
As if I'd let you get away!
What are you doing?
A mysterious extraterrestrial creature stole my doll and ran away.
Piko!
You mean him?
Potato isn't an extraterrestrial creature.
He's a wild dog from my neighbourhood.
That thing was actually a dog?
Piko! Pikopiko!
I see...
Huh?
Pikopiko! Pikopikopiko! Pikori!
I see...
I'm sorry for the trouble we've caused you.
Why are you apologizing?
That's because Potato took your doll and ran all the way here.
Apparently, he wanted to play with you.
You understand what he's saying?
Yeah, he's a friend.
Right, Potato?
Pikopiko!
It seems there are worlds on the planet that I don't know.
Sorry.
Are you... hurt?
Oh, this?
Well, uh...
No, I'm still keeping that a secret.
I'm Kirishima Kano. Who are you?
I'm Kunisaki Yukito.
Are you free by any chance?
Yeah.
All right! I'll name you Freefreeplanetling Number 2!
Who's Number 1?
Me! And Potato is Number 3.
Piko!
What does a Freefreeplanetling do?
You're just free.
That's the fate of a Freefreeplanetling.
Potato, we're free, right?
Pikopiko!
I have to go to school now, so we must part here.
Aren't you a Freefreeplanetling?
You actually believed something like that? You're such a kid!
See you!
Are all the ones wearing that uniform weird or something?
Hey!
What is it?
Have you ever wondered what you could do if you had magical powers?
What?
You looked surprised. See you!
Magic?
Yukito-san!
How was work?
A great success!
Wow, really?
Sorry, that was a lie.
There won't be business unless it's a place with more people.
Hey, why is it so quiet even though it's commuting hour?
Well, this station has already been shut down.
Say that earlier!
Gao!
Ouch!
Why did you hit me?
Haruko told me to warn you whenever you use that phrase.
Oh! How cute!
Huh? Tohno-san?
An acquaintance?
Yeah.
What are you panicking about?
H-Hello!
Hello. What a coincidence.
Y-Yes, a great coincidence.
I was surprised.
What were you doing?
Basking in the sun.
Huh?
Just kidding. It's evening right now.
Hey, who's this?
This is Tohno Minagi-san, my classmate.
She's smart. Her grades are at the top of her class, and she's the president of the Astronomy Club.
Please call me Tohno as much as possible.
Hey! Minagi!
Yukito-san... like a leaf!
Hey, let's hurry and continue blowing bubbles!
Right now, I'm at my best!
Come on!
Is that girl your younger sister?
No, I'm Minagi's friend.
Who are you?
I'm Tohno-san's classmate.
That hurt.
What?! Are you Minagi's classmate too?
I'm an innocent passer-by who was bowled over by you.
I know! Minagi, this is a perverted serial kidnapper who has come to take Michiru!
I'm on this side too.
Who's a serial kidnapper?!
Not good! He's excited! Damsel in distress!
Wow, it had a great sound.
Kamio-san, this is?
Kunisaki Yukito-san. He's a traveller who is staying at my house right now.
A traveller?
There's no hope if you're a perverted serial kidnapper with no place to stay!
Kamio-san, we should be leaving soon.
Aww, I was finally able to make nice bubbles too.
Let's keep going. Kamikami too!
Kamikami... me?
It'll be dark soon, so let's do it tomorrow.
I'll make lunch, so...
See you, Kamiya!
Bye-bye!
Kunisaki Yukito!
Yeah?
Geez, you should just go away!
Whaaaaaaaat?
Hey, for tomorrow's lunch, can you make hamburgers?
All right.
Really? Hurray!
Did I do something to that brat?
Hmm, I don't know.
In the end, I didn't make a single yen.
When we met yesterday, you were doing the same thing there.
I've always turned my thoughts to the sky since I was young.
Why?
I don't know.
It's just...
I have a feeling that my other self is there.
Isn't that romantic? The thought that the real me is in the sky sounds so wonderful.
Being able to see so far and with everything on earth seeming insignificant,
you'd probably feel very gentle.
Misuzu... You're...
For me, that was the beginning of a summer...
...as short as a star's twinkle and as long as eternity.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
What I'm looking for might be the other you.
I'm not cut out to be a parent. I should have stayed alone.
I had a dream. A strange dream about the sky.
I was in the sky.
It was a world I'd never seen before.
Everything extends endlessly.
Say, do you have wings in your dreams?
Episode 2