How many days has it been since you came?
You're probably beginning to understand what's happening in this place.
Its appearance alone seems fitting for this world, but in reality, it is no different from a prison.
When you say "winged person", you mean a messenger of the gods, right?
They are the beings who can speak directly to the gods, battle against famines and epidemics, and purify and pray.
I thought you would be living a little better than this.
Just having wings doesn't make one a messenger of the gods.
Where are your wings?
I've concealed them.
Normally, I take the form of a human.
What are you doing?!
Nothing, it's just that you have a good figure, so...
Do you touch and check each time someone has a good figure?!
You good-for-nothing!
What's so funny, Uraha?
The sight of you being embarrassed.
Forget that.
Just don't sneak up on us each time.
The fact that you've called Ryuuya-sama today too...
Kanna-sama, it seems that you've taken a very, very strong liking to Ryuuya-sama.
That's not the case!
I'm teaching this good-for-nothing, impolite and idiotic fool some manners.
This really is the first time there has been someone like you, Ryuuya-sama.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Episode 8
Kanna-sama, please accept this.
I found something like this a moment ago in the cellar.
Summer is at its height, so it's unusual to find ice.
I felt that I had to report this, so I brought it with me like this.
Mm, that is a mysterious occurrence.
It's a serious crime to go in there without permission.
Oh oh dear dear.
Dangerous, dangerous.
I knew you two were in it together.
It's cold.
Ryuuya-dono, you should try some as well.
It's also a serious crime to taste something that's offered to Kannabi-sama.
You're also eating while saying that, aren't you?
The three of us sharing ice like this is like...
We're like a half-dead family trying to avoid starvation under cold skies and without any food.
What a fun metaphor!
What is a family like?
Let's see...
Simply put...
Stick.
Hey!
Don't stick to me when it's this hot!
Wait, wait, don't feel so down.
Come closer.
Stick.
Didn't I tell you not to stick to me?
You don't have to go that far.
Stick.
Why are you sticking to me as well?
Well, I just felt like it.
Both of you, get away from me!
So you're teasing me...
Family means to live huddling together.
Since when has Kanna been living like this?
Ever since you took up this post, she has lived in this cheery way.
Not that.
When was it that she began to live in this palace?
That I don't know,
since I haven't been here for more than half a year.
However, I have heard that for as long as she could remember,
she's been trapped like this, moving from place to place without anyone to talk to.
Ryuuya-sama.
It's my shift now.
Oh.
Why are you so frightened?
Um... Well, I have been uneasy ever since I came here.
I'm afraid that I'll be punished by the gods if I'm near Kannabi-sama for no reason.
It seems, from what I've seen, that that doesn't happen.
I hear that there are many people who dislike or fear the winged being.
I really want to return to my normal duties soon.
Is something wrong, Kanna?
Ryuuya-dono, do you dream?
Sometimes.
What's wrong?
Did you have a scary dream or something that kept you up all night?
It was a dream of the distant past.
A young me was sitting in similar darkness.
I couldn't see anything.
I couldn't even tell whether my body was there.
I felt tearful and sad.
But even then, I could not cry.
The dream was of those days.
There are times when I see just one light.
It's the shadow of a person.
But if I try to chase it, it disappears.
I've had the same kind of dream not once, but numerous times.
Ryuuya-dono, do you know who it is?
Your mother, right?
I don't remember my mother.
Dreams happen when you remember a scene that you've seen somewhere.
That's why you dream, even if you don't remember those things.
My body remembers?
Then I guess it's not a bad dream.
I want to see her.
I have never felt that being alone would be this painful.
It has been decided that Kannabi no Mikoto move to the north shrine,
to propagate the message to protect and give to this country.
Quiet!
It has been decided that she leave at the sunset of Saturday, on the Taisho.
Are we going to serve with her?
No, we will all remain and follow the orders of Kaikon.
I heard what happened.
Something like that happens every year around this time.
I didn't know until this morning.
This is where I will part with you and Uraha.
We don't have many days left.
Is that all right?
Is what all right?
I'm asking whether it is all right for you to be separated from Uraha and me.
There will probably be other strange people up ahead.
Uraha and I won't be there.
Do not overestimate yourself!
Do I look that weak?
I can live, even if you aren't here.
I've lived alone like that before.
Weren't you sad?
Don't you want to see your mother?
I'm telling you that there's nothing you can do if you cannot see someone, even if you want to.
Did your mother... die?
She isn't dead.
She is definitely...
thinking about me somewhere.
Uraha... Kanna-
I'm busy right now!
What are you doing?
Can't you tell?
I'm preparing for a journey.
Kanna is the only one leaving.
We're staying here.
Isn't that why we're taking her away before that happens?
It's too much for poor Kanna-sama to live like this forever.
Can I ask you something?
Why do you worry about Kanna so much?
I'd like to ask you the same thing.
Let's see...
To put it bluntly,
there's no one worth teasing as much as she is.
That's exactly it, right?
Hey, Kanna.
Wake up.
Good morning.
A-A suspicious person!
Shh!
Don't cause a fuss. We need to talk to you.
Don't you want to see your mother?
Due to my position, I cannot under any circumstance go against the Kannabi no Mikoto's direct order,
so if you tell me to reunite you with your mother, I will risk my life for that.
Will you order me as my master?
You're... all right with that?
You're the one who decides that.
Then I will order you.
Lead me to my mother.
[Note: Spoken in ultra-formal language]
Shou Hachii Ge.
Daisakan of Saemon, Ryuuya.
I swear that I will not stray from Kannabi no Mikoto's order.
Kanna-sama!
Hurry!
Ryuuya-sama, please rest for a while.
No one seems to have noticed yet.
It's just a matter of time.
There will eventually be a huge commotion.
It's rather late of me to say this, but we've done a very bold thing.
Don't say things like that when we've come this far.
Look there!
What exactly happened to the palace?
I don't know.
But it seems that we should distance ourselves from here as soon as possible.
What is it?
It seems that we've been surrounded.
Kanna, Uraha,
we're going to run as fast as we can.
Run!
Throw down your weapon.
Answer my questions honestly.
You're an easterner, aren't you?
Why are you after the Kannabi no Mikoto?
I don't know.
We were ordered to.
What were you planning to do with the Kannabi no Mikoto?
Whose orders are you following?
I don't know!
We were just ordered by our leader.
I see.
Stop it!
You... were you planning to kill this person?
If I don't do that, our lives will be in danger.
You should feel ashamed, you fool!
You kill people without regret?
Kanna-sama.
I don't want to be protected by someone like that!
I order you.
I will not tolerate any killing as long as you consider me your master.
Understand that.
I understand.
But do you think we'll be able to survive from now on without killing one person?
I feel that it will be easy for you, Ryuuya-sama.
Heh, as if it's easy.
Where exactly did you find a kimono like this?
I took the laundry someone left hanging to dry by the river.
Of course, I left some payment.
It looks pretty good on you, Kanna.
R-Really?
You have weird taste.
Kanna-sama is so funny.
When she was changing, she said that she cannot let you see clothes that don't look good on her.
Idiot! Don't say that!
It isn't that good, is it?
When the three of us partake of dried rice like this, it's as if...
We're some court nobles, degraded to backwater places, wetting our food with tears of shame.
What an elegant metaphor!
It's otedama.
Apparently, they were in the kimono.
But it's unusual for them to be made of cloth.
Usually, we use rocks, but it must be made of cloth to prevent children from getting hurt.
Can I try it too?
If you learn a little, you will definitely become good.
Not everyone succeeds the first time.
Perseverance is important in everything.
I-It just slipped a little.
You mustn't just use strength.
Just throw them to about where your eyes are.
I know!
I never knew that you were this clumsy.
Oh, Kanna-sama, I feel so sorry for you.
Don't say such exaggerated things!
I hear that your mother is being held captive on a holy mountain in Kishuu.
What kind of place is Kishuu?
Is it far from here?
It is.
It's over the mountains, so it's especially far.
Let's proceed cautiously, so we can avoid being found by our pursuers.
H-H-Hot!
Here, let me.
It's been a month already, but you haven't been getting any better.
There are times when I do it well.
Three days ago, I did three consecutive cycles.
Oh?
What a great accomplishment.
You're making fun of me, aren't you?
When we're gathered like this around a fire in the mountains...
It sounds like a handsome man regretting.
Though kidnapping the princess and running away was fine, he realised that taking care of her was another matter.
What a truly touching metaphor!
It's not really a metaphor; it's almost literally true.
Kishuu is right ahead.
Our days of living like this are numbered.
Why do they all look like they're having fun?
Well, when one breaks all of one's bonds like them, one's world feels much less gloomy.
That's not all.
Everyone believes...
...that his or her wishes will definitely reach the heavens.
Who will take them to the heavens?
That's...
I have wings, but I cannot fly in the skies.
I've tried ever since I was young.
I can't even rise like a leaf in the breeze, much less reach the heavens.
They're good-for-nothing wings.
Even then, if I wish, will my wishes really reach the heavens?
They will.
All you have to do is wish with your heart.
They will definitely be granted.
Right, Uraha?
Yes, that's right!
Hey, Uraha.
That's ticklish.
Hey!
It's too quiet.
Don't let your guard down.
We should already be at the holy mountain.
It appears that there is a shield.
Please be quiet.
I have a feeling that this is the place we've been looking for.
You can tell?
Yes.
Though... it's nothing special...
Do not make a sound.
Militant monks, eh?
This area is off-limits to women!
What does a country samurai want from this holy mountain?!
[Note: People believed that foxes and raccoons transformed to confuse and deceive them]
It seems that I was deceived by a wild fox when I was walking elatedly on the night paths.
No, maybe it was just a wild raccoon dog.
We can't allow you to escape,
since we won't be able to touch you when you pass the shield.
Ryuuya-dono, behind you!
I will not allow any killing from now on.
Ryuuya-dono!
Don't come!
What... are you planning?
We won't let you see... the Yao Bikuni.
Yao... Bikuni...
Ryuuya-dono!
You've regained consciousness!
I'm glad!
It appears that the worst has passed.
How long... was I asleep?
A whole day.
Rest assured.
We've already crossed the shield.
The monks cannot chase us.
I see.
I will get some water.
Ryuuya-dono.
Ah.
Are you all right, Kanna?
I... forbade you to kill,
but now... come to think of it... that was... my...
Since I'm faithful,
Whatever your order is, I will follow it.
For example, if you ordered me not to die, I will not die, no matter what.
Then...
I order you.
No,
this is not an order, but my wish.
Ryuuya-dono,
I don't want you to die.
[Note: Spoken much more informally]
Okay.
I promise you.
Here?
Yes, I'm sensing something.
Mother is here?
Most likely.
Watch out.
Stop.
If you try recklessly to pull me into a war, know that you will not leave here alive.
I am the protector of Kannabi no Mikoto, Ryuuya.
Excuse me, but I gather that you are Kannabi no Mikoto's mother?
Kanna?
Is that you, Mother?
My wings can neither flap nor fly,
but if you have the same things as me...
Kanna!
Mother!
You who call yourself Ryuuya,
take Kanna and descend from this mountain immediately.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
What do you plan to do with me?
We will have you leave here.
After that, we will have you live happily ever after with Kanna-sama.
Mother.
Let us live in a small cottage somewhere peaceful.
Dreams are not always painful.
It was fun.
Kanna!
Why?
Why does everyone... leaving just me?
Episode 9