Oh.
What's going on?
Kano!
Hang on!
Hey, Kano!
Don't be violent.
It hurts.
Onee-chan...
Oh?
Yukito-kun?
Where am I?
What happened...
...to me?
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Can you stand?
Yes.
O-Oh.
Thanks.
It's all right.
More importantly, do you remember anything?
No.
I'm sorry.
There's really no need to apologise.
What was that field of pampas grass a moment ago?
You saw it too?
Kano!
Oh?
What's the meaning of this?!
All right, listen carefully.
It's true that I'm holding her like this,
but we didn't end up like this in the way that you're thinking.
It's not like I gave alcohol to an innocent girl and took her to a secluded place...
No questions asked!
Wait, wait!
Onee-chan?
Oh.
Episode 3
I deeply apologise for doing such a bad thing.
I wasn't aware of the details, so I became a little upset.
You call that a little, you violent intimidator?
Did you say something?
Nope, nothing at all.
I'll apologise too.
I'm sorry, Yukito-kun.
And, um...
Kamio,
Misuzu Kamio.
I see.
Your face looks familiar, but...
I don't stand out very much, so...
You and I are acquainted though,
since you've been here a few times to receive check-ups.
In the end, weird things really did happen on your birthday.
But that just makes it all the more memorable.
Why don't you make friends with Kano instead of just playing with me all the time?
The two of you might get along pretty well.
After all, you're both pretty weird.
I guess.
Oh.
What's wrong?
I forgot to pick up today's salary for my part-time work.
Go on home.
If that's the case, then tomorrow...
She might be evasive if I try to pick it up tomorrow.
Hey, part-time sala...
Hm?
They've already gone to sleep?
How careless...
Geez!
I told you not to turn on lights so suddenly.
Sorry.
But I can't properly check up on you in the dark, right?
Hm... Kano, you've matured a lot too, huh?
Hey, stop it, Onee-chan!
Don't touch me in weird places.
This is a proper clinical technique known as "examination by touch."
In examination tests, you don't caress!
Huh?
There was a weird sound just now.
What?
Nyaa.
Oh, I guess it was just a cat.
But we don't keep cats at our house.
Oh, I must be hearing things then.
I guess.
So, Kano, let's continue.
Kano?
Hey, what's wrong, Kano?
I see.
Has it come?
It's been a while.
Again?
Stop it already!
Always, always, repeating the same words!
This girl... my life,
my one treasure.
You're wrong!
Kano is mine!
She's my precious sister!
Huh?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Why is Onee-chan hugging me?
You were falling asleep.
What?
You came and hugged me, so I held you in return.
Huh?
I don't remember at all.
That's why I've been telling you to hurry up and sleep, right?
Okay.
But can we be like this for a little longer?
You did this for me when Daddy died, remember?
That's right.
Onee-chan,
you have a nice smell.
Wah, the cicadas came in from the ventilation fan again!
Wah, the soy sauce container fell!
Wah, the salad oil spilled!
Wah, Yukito-san's bacon egg turned out horribly.
Hey, Misuzu!
I won!
V!
Yukito-san?
Did something happen?
Hey, something happened to this food, right?
Nothing happened, nothing.
What's with those "oi, he's actually eating it" eyes?
My eyes aren't like that, not like that.
Yukito-san, is it good?
Yeah.
Really?
It doesn't taste like cicadas?
What do you mean by that?!
Nothing. Nothing at all.
Yukito-san?
Hm?
We're here.
Oh, sorry.
What's wrong?
Are you thinking about something?
Sort of...
Something that happened yesterday?
Sort of... Various things...
Then I'll see you later, okay?
Okay.
G-Gao.
Hey.
At least work your salary's worth.
I went through everything once already.
Then I have something else for you to do.
Come over here.
What's with those eyes?
If you want to say something, why don't you just say it clearly?
However, I won't agree to a salary increase.
That's not it.
Then what is it?
Actually, it's about last night...
Hey!
Have you seen Potato?
Potato?
Come to think of it, I haven't seen him around.
Yes, I've been looking for him for a while, but I can't seem to find him!
Potato?
Pikopiko!
Potato, come out.
Piko!
Potato?
Pikopiko!
Potato... where could he be?
The sun's starting to set now.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Let's search.
Not here either.
We've ran out of places to search.
Can't you search with your magic?
What?
I think that my magic is for different things...
I see.
I was told when I was given this bandanna
to keep it on until I became an adult.
I can't take it off until then, no matter what.
If I did that, I'd be able to use magic.
Who did you get it from?
I was small, so I don't remember very well,
but this has been wrapped around my wrist ever since.
It's been troublesome at times, especially during swimming and body check-ups, and I was even bullied a few times.
I see.
But you know, Onee-chan always saved me.
That's why we've been able to come this far.
Oh...
We've finally arrived at school.
No matter what, there's no way he'd be in a place like this.
Eh? What is it?
Wait!
Hey, Yukito-kun?
What's gotten into you?
I just realised where Potato is.
Really?
It's right over there.
Right over there?
You mean, at school?
Yeah.
He should be in here.
What?
In here?
Can that be?
Oh!
Potato!
Pika.
Finally found you!
Geez, don't ever make me worry like that again.
Pikopiko.
But why were you in a place like this?
And Yukito-kun, how did you know that he was there?
That's... well... um... what do you call it?
Piko pikopik...
Well, it's...
...a kind of magic.
Right?!
Piko.
Okay, Potato, from now on, you can't disappear without saying anything.
It's a pity that you don't behave as well as you talk.
But I'm glad.
Kano.
What?
Do you really not remember anything about what happened yesterday?
No.
I'm sorry.
I really am.
No, it doesn't matter.
Yukito-kun, will you listen to something?
Sure.
I'll listen to anything you want to say.
I hardly remember anything about my mum.
Apparently, her body wasn't very strong from the beginning.
She became sick right after she gave birth to me and passed away when I was about 3.
Dad would often say, "Your mum was like you."
Still, I couldn't imagine her very well.
Oh, it's not so bad; I wasn't very sad.
Onee-chan became a substitute for my mum, and dad was always around too.
But that means that Onee-chan was without a mum for a long time, right?
Recently, I've thought that that wasn't fair.
Dad was always busy managing the clinic, and his health collapsed from working too hard.
I could only watch.
The same thing is happening now.
Onee-chan works and cares for me, but I can't do anything to help her.
I'm not of much help either.
That's not true, definitely not!
If...
If I could use magic...
I...
would use it to meet my mum.
I want to meet her and apologise...
...for many things.
You should thank her, not apologise.
Eh?
Your mother is the reason that you're here right now, right?
If someone told me, "I'm sorry that you gave birth to me,"
I'd be furious.
I see.
That's true.
What about your mum, Yukito-kun?
What kind of person is she?
She's not here anymore.
She's been where your mum is for a long time now.
Is that so?
My mum was looking for a girl in the sky.
A girl?
Yeah.
"On the other side of this sky, there is a girl with wings."
That was my mum's favourite saying.
I'm looking for that girl too.
Then someday, if I'm able to fly in the sky, I'll search for that girl for you.
Kamio
I'm home.
You're late.
Are you alone?
The girl is in her room.
She wasn't feeling very well,
so she's sleeping alone.
Shouldn't you be with her?
If I were there, she'd only become more conscientious.
There's no reason for a child to be conscientious of her parent.
There are many factors, even though I'm her mother.
Misuzu, I'm coming in.
Oh, Yukito-san.
I heard that you aren't feeling well.
Yeah.
But it's nothing serious.
Sorry that I couldn't pick you up today.
It's okay.
After all, you're busy with many things.
I see.
You really like dinosaurs, don't you?
Why does she like dinosaurs so much?
Who knows?
She's been like that since she was a child.
You don't know anything about her even though she's your own daughter.
Did you forget that yesterday was her birthday?
Hey, does that girl act strangely during the day?
Isn't she always strange?
No, not like that.
Oh, if there's nothing, then it's all right.
What are you talking about?
Now, enough with this trivial talk; it's finally today's main event:
The Erotic Confessions Corner!
How did we end up going there?!
Oh, I'm starting to get hot just by saying the title!
Are you a pervert or something?!
Romantic?
Yes, romantic.
That's because dinosaurs flourished for a long time, but then faced their end, extinction.
It's kind of sad and makes my heart palpitate.
Do you still have those dreams?
Yes, I do.
In my dreams, I'm going back in time.
How do you know that?
I don't know how to describe it,
but I know.
It's because the smell of the wind, the breeze caressing my skin, the flow of air, and the passing of the seasons.
I know that I'm going back in time.
I've never heard of a dream like that.
Yukito-san...
Hmm?
I wonder where my dream is taking me.
I'm coming now!
Potato!
Please try not to get hit by accident!
Today is the suika wari?
Yes, at Kano's behest.
Aren't you spoiling her a bit?
Piko.
Ready...
Set...
See you tomorrow!
There's no one here.
So it's impossible to make money here too.
Yukito Kunisaki!
Yukito-san!
Don't body bash me every time!
Why didn't you come yesterday?
Yesterday?
We waited for you!
Minagi seemed sad.
It's all right.
Stop acting so strong!
Sorry, I was a little busy yesterday.
As punishment, you'll live here from today on!
Eh?
Huh?
What are you saying?
Hey, didn't you want me to leave this town in the first place?
The circumstance was different!
Wow! It stood!
I don't get it at all.
I won.
It really is mysterious, isn't it?
Kunisaki-san, you have such a wonderful special talent.
Applause.
Clap clap clap.
I can use a bit of what is called "magic."
Magical powers?
The world is full of mystery.
Well then, a special thank you.
[Ticket: Usable Worldwide, Rice Ticket, 1000 Yen]
Ta-da.
Kunisaki-san?
A girl with wings?
Yeah.
I'm searching for the girl that my mum sought.
Do you think I'm strange?
When I was a child, there was a picture book like that at home.
Picture book?
Inside that picture book, there was a girl with pure white wings on her back,
and I, with a childish heart, wanted to fly into the sky with her someday.
There's nothing strange about you, even if the purpose of your journey is to search for that girl,
because everyone has a different destination in mind.
The stars will probably be pretty tonight too.
Minagi!
Help me!
I can't do it well at all!
I'll come right now, Michiru.
A destination, huh?
Done with today's homework!
Yukito-san?
Hmm?
Let's play cards.
C-A-R-D-S.
Huh?
What is it so suddenly?
I've been wanting to play cards with you for a long time.
Do it yourself.
Ah, we have come from a faraway planet...
I want to play cards.
Mizuki-kun!
Are you there?
Kano disappeared again.
Did she come here?
She's not at the shrine?
I've searched the shrine.
I'll go to the school.
I'll leave that way to you guys.
Okay.
Yukito-san, do you have any idea where she might be?
Not really. Let's just search where we can.
Kano!
Kirishima-san?
Piko!
Potato.
Pi-ka!
Is he asking us to follow him?
The shrine again?
But she said that she searched...
Kano!
Hey, are you all right?
Tightly clasping my only treasure...
Kano?
Then, perhaps,
by my hands...
Hey, Kano.
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
I'm writing this because I think that you'll believe me.
I've finally decided to go to the sky.
I have a feeling that if I do that, everyone can be happy.
I feel that I can meet the girl you're searching for too.
I don't know when it'll be,
but I'll definitely bring that person.
I'll be grateful if you can help my sister until I return.
Episode 4