Piko piko piko piko pikori.
That child said, "I want to see the ocean."
But I couldn't take him.
I wanted to do many things for him,
but I couldn't do a single thing,
even though summer had just begun.
Yukito-san?
Yukito-san, it's morning.
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Episode 5
Aren't you glad that Kirishima-san recovered?
Yeah.
You know, when I saw that feather, I also had a kinda mysterious feeling.
Yukito-san?
Huh? Did you say something?
You've been out of it ever since you woke up.
Well...
I just saw a dream of the past.
A dream?
It's nothing to worry about.
More importantly, do you still have those dreams?
Yes.
The dream last night was different from anything from before.
The moon was floating, and it was really bright.
I was trying to climb the sky.
My entire body was throbbing and trying to ascend higher.
And then, I heard voices.
Voices?
The voices of many people were trying to restrain me.
They echoed in my ears, so I couldn't climb anymore.
Well, see you later.
Okay.
I'm going now.
Hey, be carefu-
Wah!
It's great, isn't it, Onee-chan?
I wonder how it's walking without any strings.
Oh?
It tripped.
It stood! It stood!
This is how kids should be.
Piko piko.
Hey, shouldn't you be by Kano's side?
Oh...
So she's going to school to take care of the animals today...
Wait, why are we having a normal conversation like this?
Piko?
Hey, we have to go now.
Yup.
Doll-san, see you.
Handshake, handshake.
Let's go.
Okay.
So that's what a harmonious relationship is like, eh?
Pikori.
I worked for free again.
That Misuzu is late.
Tohno.
Oh, Kunisaki-san.
Hello.
Huh?
If you're going to say something, do it after you swallow.
Thank you for the meal.
You're welcome.
Did Misuzu come this way?
Kamio-san...
No.
I see.
Hey, hey!
Will you make hamburgers tomorrow too?
Yes.
Yay!
What a gluttonous person!
Let go!
You let go first!
Michiru.
Were you able to use the shower?
Yeah.
How did you get the keys to this place?
My father was the stationmaster here,
but he's not working here anymore.
Did he find a different job?
Oh yes,
as a token of apology for what just happened, take this.
[On the envelope: Rice Ticket]
And today...
This too.
That's the bottle I found yesterday!
This is stardust,
sand shaped like baby stars.
Wow, is it really?
Here you go.
It rustles!
Kunisaki-san too.
Here.
I can have one too?
Yes.
With this, the three of us...
...match.
This sand is something that my father gave me when I was still small.
Then isn't it something precious?
Is it all right?
Yes, if it's you and Michiru...
It seems that Kamio-san has already left.
I... see.
Is it possible that she stayed at school this late?
Maybe.
Oh, that's right. Kunisaki-san, are you busy?
Welcome... to the Astronomy Club.
The stars are out already!
What about the other club members?
There are no others.
I am the only club member.
The only?
That's why I'm Club President.
It's a really selective club.
I see.
Does she come here often?
No, this is the first time that I've brought her.
Um...
You're not going out of your way to be here?
No.
I see.
I wanted the three of us to get together and observe the stars,
because it seems that she likes you.
I don't think that's possible.
No.
She talks about you constantly when she is with me.
She likes you, Kunisaki-san.
It's really hard to believe.
I understand how she feels,
because she is half of me.
Half of you?
Michiru and I have always spent our time together like this.
So cute...
Huh?
Kunisaki-san, you're...
Me?
...always travelling alone, right?
Have you ever spent time like this?
The happiness of being with someone other than yourself...
The joy of being able to live for someone...
Even someone like me should have,
though it was in the distant past.
See you!
I'm going now!
Mmhmm, see you tomorrow.
Then it's Michiru Dash!
I'm sorry.
You don't have to escort me home.
No.
I don't really mind.
You're pretty tall.
Do you dislike tall girls?
Nah.
Since having a nice body is good.
Actually, I happen to think of it a little boastfully too.
Happen to think about it, huh?
Happen to.
The taller you are, the closer you are to the sky.
Thank you for escorting me.
Nah, it's no big deal.
Please be careful walking home.
Yeah.
Welcome home.
Oh, that person is?
A new member of the Astronomy Club.
I am?
Oh, you're...
Thank you very much for helping me.
Eh?
I told you, remember?
I carried groceries for her the other day.
I'm sorry for having you go to the trouble of walking my daughter home.
Now, come inside, Michiru.
What's wrong, Michiru?
Dinner is already prepared.
Hey, Tohno.
Goodbye.
I'm home.
[Sign: I'm working hard on my homework.]
Misuzu, I'm coming in.
Hey, wake up.
You'll catch a cold.
Oh, Yukito-san, good morning.
It's night right now.
You should have told me that supplemental classes were going to be late.
Sorry, I forgot.
Jeez.
This...
You're keeping a picture diary?
Yes.
It's my choice of assignment for the summer.
Captain!
Why did you betray me?!
Weak soul!
I won't allow you to shamelessly act against this progress!
Members of the troop!
If I die, who will do it?
Give it to me!
If you really want it, kill me and take it!
Geh! Hey!
That was the best part!
Let's play cards.
You're really persistent.
I want to play cards with you.
Serious?
Yes, serious.
[Note: Yukito says "No matter what" in the Kansai dialect often used in stand up comedies (and by Haruko).]
No matter what?
Yes, no matter what?
Okay okay.
I'll play with you.
Yay.
Then what do you want to play?
Old Maid?
Poker?
Make it something simple that doesn't require thinking.
Then let's play Concentration.
Oh.
What's wrong?
Eh?
No, it's nothing.
I messed up.
Are you... crying?
I'm not crying.
I can play.
I have to try my hardest.
What's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
I'm all right.
I'm all right!
Misuzu!
What's wrong?
Hey!
Hang on!
Misuzu!
Misuzu suddenly...
I know.
Can you step outside for a while?
Misuzu.
Calm down, Misuzu!
She's been like this ever since she was little.
She becomes like that when she's on the verge of being friends with someone.
When she's on the verge of being friends?
I've had the doctor at the clinic look at her, and I've even tried going to a big hospital.
They couldn't do anything.
I was told it was probably a psychological thing and that she'd get better when she got older,
but she actually had an attack at school today too.
I was contacted at my workplace, so I went to pick her up on my bike and took her straight home.
I see.
I was expecting and hoping that she'd be all right with you,
since she's all right when she's with me.
Are you really leaving?
She'll have these attacks as long as I'm here, right?
I'll try distancing myself for a while.
I see.
Tell her that I'll continue walking her to and from school just like before.
Come eat every now and then.
You weren't able to stay at my house because of me.
Aren't you lonely being by yourself?
No, I'm alone when I sleep and when I get up, but I'm all right because the number of my friends increased without my knowing.
You have some friends too, right?
No, I don't.
I'm always alone,
because I start crying when I'm about to make a friend.
Everyone always runs away from me.
But you have Haruko, right?
You aren't alone.
She... isn't my real mum.
Really?
Haruko-san is actually my aunt.
I was dumped onto her because I was a weird kid.
Haruko-san didn't want me, but I ended up living here.
Since I don't want to cause her trouble, we live separately under one roof.
That's why I don't say anything.
I'm really a bother, so I'm always playing by myself to avoid causing any more trouble.
Looking for weird juices, or playing cards...
Misuzu.
Just keep smiling.
V!
Okay then, see you later.
Take care.
What's wrong?
Minagi isn't coming.
She has school, right?
She'll come eventually.
She's not supposed to be at school today.
Did I do something bad?
Give me that for a second.
Give it back!
Just watch, all right?
Stop it!
Indirect kiss!
Don't talk about adult stuff.
That was great!
Do it again!
Bubbles are pretty.
They're empty, just like the sky.
She isn't coming.
Yeah.
I wonder if something happened.
Let's try going to Tohno's house.
Minagi's... house?
Yeah.
If she isn't coming, we should go see her.
What's wrong?
I don't want to go to her house.
You're friends, right?
You've never gone?
Then I'll go by myself.
After all, I have to pick Misuzu up too.
Thank you for walking me home.
Sorry, I have to excuse myself here today.
You're not eating dinner?
I have somewhere to go.
See you tomorrow.
Who is this?
I met you yesterday, remember?
I'm a new member of the Astronomy Club.
What?
I'm running an errand.
Can you call your daughter?
Daughter?
Has she gone somewhere?
We... don't have a daughter.
What?
Are you sure you've got the right house?
Hey!
You're joking, right?!
What are you doing here, skipping your part-time job?
Tohno-san's mother was troubled in her heart.
I occasionally monitored her condition.
She convinced herself that her eldest daughter, Minagi-san, is her second daughter who passed away.
That was quite a while back.
But there seems to have been a sudden change in her condition.
At the same time that she realised that her younger daughter wasn't living, she forgot about Minagi-san.
Inside of her, she believed that both of her daughters never existed.
I was supposed to have a younger sister,
a precious younger sister named Michiru.
My mother was sad because I was close to my father.
The Michiru who was about to be born was supposed to fill the hole in her heart.
If you had one wish, what would it be?
Hm...
Let's see...
I want a younger sister!
My mother lost a vent for her feelings, so she chose to continue watching a dream.
And I... was a fragment of that dream.
But last night, she apparently saw herself in a dream having a miscarriage of Michiru.
According to Kirishima-sensei, Mother accepted reality after seeing that.
This morning, when she saw me, Mother said,
"Who are you?"
You can't go back?
This is the end of my dream.
It is the end of my dream in which I lived as Michiru.
My wings have now forgotten how to fly,
because I always just pretended to flap.
Is there a use for wings that cannot fly?
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Welcome home!
Preview
Maybe you're more suited to travels than I am.
Will you come with me, Tohno?
Eh?
It's not good being like this, after all.
I want to show you the world,
the real world, not a dream world.
Everything started from my sin.
Episode 6