Why?
Why must I leave the mountain?
[Note: Spoken in a fairly formal language]
With all due respect, I am Kanna-sama's guardian.
I cannot go against her wishes.
What do you plan to do with me?
We will have you leave here.
After that, we will have you live happily ever after with Kanna-sama.
If there were many people like you in the world, our fates might be different.
Please step back.
Mother!
You must not come!
My body is already tainted.
Tainted?
You must not come close to me.
Mother...
kieru hikoukigumo bokutachi wa miokutta
消える飛行機雲　僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading contrails go by.
mabushikute nigeta
眩しくて逃げた
I ran away because it was too bright.
kuyashikute yubi o hanasu
悔しくて指を離す
I let go of your hands because it hurt.
todokanai basho ga mada tooku ni aru
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away.
negai dake himete mitsumeteru
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I gaze at it with a wish locked away inside.
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
kodomotachi wa natsu no senro aruku
子供たちは夏の線路　歩く
The children walk on the summer railway tracks,
ryoute ni wa tobitatsu kibou o
両手には飛び立つ希望を
with hope that will take flight in my hands.
kieru hikoukigumo oikakete oikakete
消える飛行機雲　追いかけて追いかけて
I chased and chased the fading contrails.
kono oka o koeta ano hi kara kawarazu itsumademo
この丘を越えたあの日から変わらずいつまでも
Nothing changed since the day we went past that hill.
massugu ni bokutachi wa aru youni
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
I hope we can be our honest selves forever,
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
watatsumi no youna tsuyosa o mamoreru yo kitto
わたつみのような強さを守れるよ　きっと
and definitely protect this Poseidon-like strength.
Episode 9
Did you say that your name was Uraha?
Are you the one who broke this barrier and found a way out?
Yes.
It was as if I was being beckoned by something...
You seem to be gifted with a special power.
Power?
Quiet!
Is that a bird?
That's a whistling arrow!
It's the signal of a battle.
An army from somewhere is trying to invade this mountain.
Mother!
Captured!
What?!
That arrow was mine!
Don't look!
So this is the power of a winged being...
Mother!
Don't pull out the arrows!
What are you saying?!
The blood will only spurt out.
Mother.
You must not...
touch...
No!
No! No! No!
Kanna-sama!
Kanna!
Mother!
Kanna.
You are such a hopeless child.
I've told you many times, yet...
Mother!
I had forgotten for a long time...
...that human flesh was this warm.
If this is fate...
Kanna, listen carefully...
...to the ancient prayer that was to die with me.
I will now bestow it upon you.
If possible, I wanted you to live as a normal girl, without being entwined in the fate of winged beings.
Mother.
Power...
Wind...
Now... the thing... we finally... inherit...
A dream that stars see...
A dream that stars see?
What are you talking about?
[Note: Ryukyu = Taiwan or Okinawa]
A wing fitting for faraway Ryukyu.
A way for our souls...
This is the end.
Please forgive me.
This is, above all, our duty.
Mother.
Now, Kanna.
It is your turn.
How have you continued your trip?
It's all right for me to say?
Um, I was living in a palace in the mountains until a while back...
In truth, I had never been on such a fun voyage before.
It was all thanks to Ryuuya-dono and Uraha.
Kanna-sama.
It seems that your mother is tired.
Don't you have something you'd like to show her?
I trained a lot, so that when I met you, I could show you.
I can really, really do it!
Next time, I will definitely throw them well!
There.
This time.
It will go well next time, next time, for sure!
Why won't you go around?
We're in front of Mother!
Why won't you go around?!
I've been training a long time just for this day, so why?!
You are very good.
You tried your very best, really.
Mother.
Continue; I'll be watching you the whole time.
I understand.
Uraha-dono,
please do not think of this mother as heartless.
I won't.
Ryuuya-dono,
there is no need for a funeral.
Do not touch my body; just leave it here as it is.
With this, I have no more regrets.
I... just wanted to feel with someone.
If I could... entwine my wings with hers...
and fly to wherever we wanted in the summer sky.
To fly with her...
Mother?
Mother.
Mother! Mother!
Kanna, that's enough. That's enough already!
Mother!
Let go!
Won't you let go?!
Mother doesn't lie.
Mother said I was good!
If I can't do otedama well, then Mother will become a liar!
I must be able to do it!
Mother... Mother is watching!
Mother is!
Kanna-sama!
By such crude arrows...
Kanna-sama.
Ryuuya-dono.
Thank you for doing your job as my guardian.
It was only for a short time,
but I...
I...
Ryuuya-dono!
Mother!
Ryuuya-sama, have some water.
I'm fine. Give it to Kanna, please.
It's my order.
Drink.
Is this all the water?
I see.
Let's all drink it.
Drink the rest.
When the three of us huddle together, it's like...
We're a friendly family.
You're the one who said that a true family is one that sticks together so much that it becomes hard to breathe.
That is really true.
The two of you, do you have wishes?
What are you saying so suddenly?
Let's see...
When you suddenly say something like that...
To escape from this siege, even if it means my life.
At the very least, I'll let Kanna escape alive.
I have one.
I'd like to live with Kanna-sama and Ryuuya-sama forever.
That might be good too.
Let us live in a small cottage somewhere peaceful.
In that case, I could get us food by ploughing fields or hunting.
If it's near the ocean, we can fish too.
Ocean, huh?
If we're going to bother, I'd like it to be near a warm sea in the west.
What is an ocean like?
What, you don't know?
I've heard that it's an incredibly large puddle, but I've never seen one with my own eyes.
Even if it's a puddle, it's all salt water.
You're deceiving me again, aren't you?
It's true, Kanna-sama.
Also, the ocean is as wide as the sky.
What?
[Note: High quality, expensive food]
You can eat as many red sea breams and abalone as you want!
Is that true?
Well, that depends on my fishing skills.
There are probably also summer festivals in villages near the ocean.
Yeah.
They have them everywhere.
Next time, let's dance, all three of us.
Yeah, just watching is boring.
This is a dream.
My dream.
Dreams are not always painful.
It was fun.
Kanna.
The two of you, do not move from here, no matter what.
I could forget about my wings when I was with you, Ryuuya-dono.
Kanna...
This is my final order.
Live...
happily...
forever.
Kanna!
Don't be afraid!
What is this voice?
It's a subjugation curse.
The monks are cursing Kanna-sama.
[Note: Sutra = Buddhist scripture]
Do not stop chanting the sutras!
To protect this world from the winged being, you must not hold your own lives dear!
Kanna!
Fly higher!
More!
Higher!
Kanna!
Ryuu... ya... dono...
Kanna...!!
Ryuuya-sama.
What are you...
I don't care who.
I'll die taking with me as many of those who put Kanna through that as I can.
If you get in my way, I'll kill you.
Kill me, please.
This isn't a bluff.
I'm not bluffing either.
Why would Kanna-sama be glad to see you as a monster?
Kanna isn't here anymore!
No.
I can still hear Kanna-sama's voice.
What?
It's faint, but I can hear it.
The voice of Kanna-sama, crying.
Kanna is...
We believe that you are the Kannabi no Mikoto's guardians.
We have come, under orders of our master, to take you.
The person who called us was the monk Chitoku, a high priest.
Chitoku had heard of and knew about most of the situation surrounding Kanna.
A person with wings once lived in this temple too.
Since then, this temple has watched over and sometimes even helped winged beings.
According to Chitoku, generation after generation of winged beings lived and inherited the dreams of stars,
and, since ancient times, gave many bits of wisdom to the people.
One of them is considered the source of our magical powers.
Inherited dreams?
Who knows? We do not.
Winged beings, because of their strength, were held captive by the powerful men of the day,
and used as tools of war.
Kanna's mother had taken upon herself the curses of all those who were killed in war.
She was "tainted" because of that.
Those who invaded the mountain were the Imperial Court's men.
He said that it was meant to completely eradicate the worship of winged beings and to unify the people.
Chitoku also said that Kanna was probably the last surviving winged being in this world.
Chitoku-sama, I have a request.
Please bestow magical powers upon me.
It was decided that we could live at the temple.
They said Uraha was a gem that appeared only once every hundred years.
The long days and months passed.
I will begin now.
[Note: Tamayose = calling forth spirits to oneself]
If we use the magic of tamayose, we should know what kind of dreams Kanna-sama is having.
Ryuuya-dono!
Ryuuya-dono, wake up!
It's my order!
Why won't you move?
Why won't you open your eyes?
I won't forgive you.
I won't forgive you if you die and leave me!
Why?
Why does everyone... leaving just me?
No!
That's wrong, Kanna!
I'm all right!
I'm here!
That... is what Kanna is dreaming about now.
Yes.
Are you saying that she continuously dreams this, somewhere in the sky?
The curse that the monks at the mountain placed on her is tormenting her, even now.
There's also the curse that she inherited from her mother.
It is one that weakens those who care for winged beings, eventually sending them to their deaths.
Is that why my wound will not heal?
Yes.
I can ward it off with my magic, but Ryuuya-sama, you...
When will I die?
I don't think you will last a year from now.
I see.
The curse that has taken Kanna captive will break someday.
When that happens, Kanna-sama's spirit will return to earth and will probably repeat the cycle of life.
However, transferring the spirit of a winged being to a human is like transferring the water of an ocean to a small container.
Before it finishes pouring in, the container will break.
Kanna-sama's spirit, without time to heal, will return to the cycle of life.
I have no time.
Is there any way to save Kanna?
There is just one.
Please make a child.
Huh?
If you leave behind a child, you can leave behind your will, right?
If that child cannot, your grandchild will. If your grandchild cannot, your great-grandchild will inherit your will.
And then, someday, you might find a way to save Kanna-sama.
I will help.
I understand.
However, I will dedicate all of my remaining time to you.
Yes.
Time that passes slowly.
In the back of the stone house, there is a text on winged beings that I compiled.
If our child, who will be born one day, searches for Kanna's spirit, that text should definitely be of help.
And Uraha will teach the child magic.
If the child is one who has her blood, he or she should be able to become a master.
He or she might be able to follow the path that we could not find.
I can continue my voyage, overcoming even time.
A voyage to find priceless wings.
There is nothing more I wish for.
There is nothing left for me to regret.
A bird is flying.
Yes.
You can forget if you want.
You can forget about me and Kanna and just be happy.
I don't want to.
I'm not alone.
Kanna-sama and you will continue to be by my side and guide me.
I am happy.
Is that so?
And that makes you my companion.
Yes.
Thank you, Uraha.
Somehow...
The sky is so high and clear, yet...
Ryuuya-sama!
Now, let's go, Uraha.
Kanna is waiting on the other side of that sky.
Yes.
I will go with you to the ends of the Earth.
Where is this?
Why am I here?
Oh yeah, I was by someone's side just a moment ago.
Beside someone very important to me.
It's no good.
My mind is hazy, and I can't remember.
Hey, where did you come from?
Where's your mummy?
Mother?
I wonder if it can fly?
Ooh, it's cute.
Hmm... Is it all right if I just leave it here?
All right, if I walk for a bit, turn around, and don't see it following me, then that will be our farewell.
Oh, it follows me.
Do you want to come with me?
I see.
Then let's go together.
Ready, set, go!
shiroku togireta yume no kirehashi wo tsukamaete
白く途切れた夢の切れ端をつかまえて
Trying to catch the white fragments of his dream,
shounen wa hashiru
少年は走る
a boy runs.
te wo hanashitara
手を放したら
When he lets go,
dokomademo tooku kaze no ne ni kieteyuku
どこまでも遠く風の音に消えてゆく
it disappears into the sound of the wind in the distance.
itsuka mieta yasashisa wa mou nai
いつか見えた優しさはもうない
The kindness that he once saw is now gone.
hitori fumidasu ashidake miteru
ひとり踏み出す足だけ見てる
He steps forward alone, looking only at his feet.
asa ni wa kieta ano utagoe wo itsumademo kiiteta
朝には消えたあの歌声をいつまでも聞いてた
He always listened to the song that disappeared by morning.
bokura ga nokoshita ano ashiato wo itsumademo otteta
僕らが残したあの足跡をいつまでも追ってた
He chased forever those footprints we left.
Preview
Summer vacation starts tomorrow.
It's amazing that you've become friends with something like this.
[Note: Sora = sky]
I gave it a name, Sora.
Don't you have another?
Rejected.
Piko piko pika.
Pikkori.
Piko?
How much longer do I have to live like this?
I can't do my best anymore if I'm alone.
What should I do?
Misuzu, I'm going.
Episode 10